<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Installation on KevCaz's Website</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/tags/installation/</link><description>Recent content in Installation on KevCaz's Website</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Content under CC0 1.0 Universal unless otherwise specified.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://kevcaz.github.io/tags/installation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>From Mantic Minotaur to Noble Numbat</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2024/05/2024-05-30_noble_numbat/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2024/05/2024-05-30_noble_numbat/</guid><description>Screenshot of my current desktop wallpaper, Little numbat boy by @azskalt, see The Coronation of a New Mascot: Noble Numbat. After a freezing phase that started last March, Ubuntu 24.04 codenamed Noble Numbat was released last April. It comes with a great deal of new features, listed in the release release notes.
As a Mantic Minotaur user, the option to update to Noble Numbat was presented in May, in a window that popped up after a regular update.</description></item><item><title>From Lunar Lobster to Mantic Minotaur</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2023/11/2023-11-05_from_lunar_lobster/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2023/11/2023-11-05_from_lunar_lobster/</guid><description>I have recently decided to upgrade to the most recent Ubuntu release on my Dell Precision machine, in other words, I wanted to get closer to Ubuntu&amp;rsquo;s release cycle. Previously, I would reinstall the latest long time release (LTS) every time a new update pops up (see the documentation). About 3 months ago, I switched to Ubuntu 23.04 (Lunar Lobster) and yesterday I upgraded to the October&amp;rsquo;s release, Mantic Minotaur (23.</description></item><item><title>Installing Python packages in Debian Trixie</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2023/08/2023-08-10_installing_python_packages/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2023/08/2023-08-10_installing_python_packages/</guid><description>I recently switched back to Debian testing and since last June, testing is Debian 13 (codename Trixie). As I was installing a bunch of Python packages, I got the following error:
1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 17 18 19 20 21 22 23 $ pip install numpy error: externally-managed-environment × This environment is externally managed ╰─&amp;gt; To install Python packages system-wide, try apt install python3-xyz, where xyz is the package you are trying to install.</description></item><item><title>What is wrong with Thunderbird?</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2021/06/2021-06-19_what_is_wrong/</link><pubDate>Sat, 19 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2021/06/2021-06-19_what_is_wrong/</guid><description>Few days ago, as I was trying to refresh my emails, I realize that Thunderbird (Thunderbird 78.11.0) was no longer able to retrieved my mails from Gmail. I tried to understand what was the problem but I wasn&amp;rsquo;t able to figure it out. After a while, I decided to uninstall Thunderbird and reinstall it. Things just got worst I couldn&amp;rsquo;t set any of my email accounts. For my Gmail, I tried to use OAuth2, as it is recommended (it used to work for me), but the identification protocol did not work: instead of getting the Gmail interface to login, I got an error message pointing out a lack of security (NS_ERROR_NET_INADEQUATE_SECURITY)&amp;hellip; As I did not understand why, I decided to stop speeding time on trying to find the origin of the problem.</description></item><item><title>Updating all your Python packages</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2020/01/2020-01-05_updating_all_your/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2020/01/2020-01-05_updating_all_your/</guid><description>Even if I do not frequently code in Python, my setup includes several packages of this programming language. While I was looking for a simple way to update all installed packages, I found this thread on stack overflow which helps me writing the following alias in my zsh profile:
1 2 3 alias updpy=&amp;#39;for i in $(pip list --outdated --format=columns |tail -n +3|cut -d&amp;#34; &amp;#34; -f1) do pip install --user $i --upgrade done&amp;#39; Now, when I enter updpy in my Terminal, all installed Python packages are updated.</description></item><item><title>SageMath version 8.6 on Debian Buster</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2019/07/2019-07-18_sagemath_version_8/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2019/07/2019-07-18_sagemath_version_8/</guid><description>This is a short note to follow up on a previous one where I reported the steps to install the latest release of Sage using the GitHub repository. At that time Sage version 8.3 was not available on Debian Buster but now version 8.6 is available on Buster! Given the set of dependencies of Sage, I guessed it was quite a challenge to pack it up, so &amp;#x1f44f; to the relentless Debian package maintainers because thanks to them all I need to install Sage is:</description></item><item><title>Dual Boot MacOS-Ubuntu</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2019/07/2019-07-16_dual_boot_macos/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2019/07/2019-07-16_dual_boot_macos/</guid><description>Context I must say that I have been quite unhappy with my old Mac Book Pro (mid 2012) for almost a year now. IIRC, I got it early 2013 and it served me well during my PhD but now it is kind of slow &amp;#x1f422; and often behaves weirdly on boot. Last weekend fir instance, I got a nasty black screen on boot &amp;#x1f631;. Turns out it happens frequently and there are no less than four different solutions to this issue &amp;#x1f631; (in my case, emptying the PRAM did the job)&amp;hellip; Windows, MacOS, blue screen, black screen, yunno&amp;hellip; I found having these issues actually rather worrisome because I care about my computer, I update it frequently and I&amp;rsquo;m actually capable of solving this kind of issues, so WTF?</description></item><item><title>My Raspberry Pi 3B</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2019/07/2019-07-12_my_raspberry_pi/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2019/07/2019-07-12_my_raspberry_pi/</guid><description>Two years ago now, I bought myself a Raspberry Pi 3B (back in 2015, I bought a model 2B and since June of this year, model 4B is out but has some issues). Even if don&amp;rsquo;t use it as much as I would like to, this small computer never ceases to amaze me! The concept is awesome, the education goals are meaningful and timely and the community is great, just check out the official website https://www.</description></item><item><title>Julia v1.1-rc1 from source</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2019/01/2019-01-13_julia_v1_1/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2019/01/2019-01-13_julia_v1_1/</guid><description>Learning more about Julia is one of the many things I attempt to do in 2019 &amp;#x1f604;. Few weeks ago, I installed Julia 1.0.0 using the GitHub repository and I decided to checkout how easy it would be to upgrade to the version to v1.1.0-rc1 (note that &amp;ldquo;rc&amp;rdquo; stands for release candidate). It was quite easy, all I had to do was:
git checkout master git pull git checkout v1.1.0-rc1 make 1h13min42sec latter, julia 1.</description></item><item><title>Thunderbird v60.3.0 solves them all!</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2018/11/2018-11-08_thunderbird_v60_3/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2018/11/2018-11-08_thunderbird_v60_3/</guid><description>As I mentioned in a previous note, when I installed the version 60.0-3 of Thunderbird I was no longer able to write new emails and so I had to downgrade to v.52.9.1. Since that time, things have gotten worst as I was no longer able to get hyperlinks opening the corresponding page in my web browser &amp;#x1f631;. I did not look for a fix, I simply coped with it waiting for an update.</description></item><item><title>Back to Thunderbird 52.9.1!</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2018/09/2018-09-18_back_to_thunderbird/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2018/09/2018-09-18_back_to_thunderbird/</guid><description>Recently, Firefox 60 and Thunderbird 60 were made available for Debian Testing and I installed them. While I was and still am happy with Firefox 60, when I tried Thunderbird I had some issues&amp;hellip; Basically, I was not able to send a message and one of my favorite add-on, Markdown-Here, was not available for this version &amp;#x1f622;. So, I needed to get the previous version back. I searched for an answer and found this one, very helpful!</description></item><item><title>My Lenovo T470p</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2018/09/2018-09-14_my_lenovo_t470p/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2018/09/2018-09-14_my_lenovo_t470p/</guid><description>When I switched from MacOS to Debian, I had no idea what laptop to buy so I searched for some information on the Internet. As expected it was hard to find reliable sources of information among websites that are obviously not neutral. After a few hours on the net, I ended up buying a Lenovo ThinkPad T470p and installed Debian on, so far so good, very happy I made this choice.</description></item><item><title>Building Sage 8.3 from sources on Debian Testing</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2018/09/2018-09-10_building_sage_8/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2018/09/2018-09-10_building_sage_8/</guid><description>Sage is a powerful mathematics software I use to do symbolic computation. Currently, there is no version available for Debian Testing, meaning you can either install the version available for the stable release or cherry pick the package available for Sid. Well I was not able to sudo apt-get the package for Stretch so I decided to use the same approach as I did for Julia (see this previous note). Basically, the sources of sage are mirrored on Github so one can clone the repository:</description></item><item><title>Building Julia 1.0.0 from sources on Debian Testing</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2018/09/2018-09-06_building_julia_1/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2018/09/2018-09-06_building_julia_1/</guid><description>You may have already heard about Julia. Well, I am not (yet) a regular user but Julia&amp;rsquo;s performances are impressive, the langage is well-thought and the community is growing super fast, I therefore pay careful attention to what&amp;rsquo;s happening on their side. Recently, version 1.0.0 was released, so I decided to replace my local version v0.4.7.9 I installed with apt-get (note that currently v0.7.0-2 is available for Sid).
There are two ways to install Julia for Debian without apt-get.</description></item></channel></rss>