<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>bookworm on KevCaz's Website</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/tags/bookworm/</link><description>Recent content in bookworm on KevCaz's Website</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Content under CC0 1.0 Universal unless otherwise specified.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 03 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://kevcaz.github.io/tags/bookworm/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Debian Bookworm setup -- update</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/linux/bookwormupdate/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/linux/bookwormupdate/</guid><description>I recently lent someone my Lenovo T470p and when I got it back, I decided to install Debian back on it (I installed Ubuntu 22.04 to make it easier to use for a non-Linux user). I went through all the installation seamlessly, but I was not able to have the wifi working. I knew it was related to firmware-iwlwifi, but I was unable to install it. As it turned out, the package was not available for bookworm (found this but looking at https://packages.</description></item><item><title>Debian Bookworm setup</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/linux/bookwormlight/</link><pubDate>Sun, 22 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/linux/bookwormlight/</guid><description>I recently decided to re-install my computer and I took the opportunity to create a gist that includes light version of my Debian 11 set-up, i.e. all the tools I used the most. Once again during the install (I use a Debian weekly build installation image) did not keep things light as I let several pieces of software be installed during the setup (e.g. LibreOffice, Inkscape). So here goes the 4th version of my bash script to install Debian on my Lenovo T470p ⬇️.</description></item><item><title>From Bullseye to Bookworm</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/linux/bookworm/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/linux/bookworm/</guid><description>Two weeks ago, Bullseye became the new stable Debian release. As I prefer using Debian testing, today, I jumped on Debian 12 codenamed Bookworm. To do so, I simply updated my source list by replacing instances of bullseye by bookworm, and then I used the combo apt update/ apt upgrade.
1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 17 18 19 20 $ apt-get update [.</description></item></channel></rss>