<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Hugo on KevCaz's Website</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/tags/hugo/</link><description>Recent content in Hugo on KevCaz's Website</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Content under CC0 1.0 Universal unless otherwise specified.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://kevcaz.github.io/tags/hugo/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>A new tree file for my notes</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2024/03/2023-03-07_a_new_tree/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2024/03/2023-03-07_a_new_tree/</guid><description>Context This section of my website is where I jot down notes that will be useful to my future self and hopefully to others. For years my notes have been organized into a set of folders that serve as categories that I thought were relevant. After 5 years and &amp;gt;120 notes, I realized that the categories were somewhat contrived (e.g. cli, linux), and that it was hard to locate a post and the assets were now managed consistently.</description></item><item><title>Time to talk about this website!</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2021/01/2021-01-29_time_to_talk/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2021/01/2021-01-29_time_to_talk/</guid><description>For this 100th SilicoNote/post, I have decided to share some notes about this website : its story and a few details about how I built the last version of it.
The short story behind my website As far as I remembered, I have built 5 different versions of my personal website. I decided to get a website when I was doing my PhD, back in 2014 (not a 100% about sure about the timeline), in order to share some of my work.</description></item><item><title>Inline Math with KaTeX</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2020/04/2020-04-19_inline_math_with/</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2020/04/2020-04-19_inline_math_with/</guid><description>For this blog, I am currently using Hugo v0.62.2, and since v0.60 Hugo by default, goldmark is used under the hood to render Markdown to HTML. Moreover, to write math I am now using Katex which is pretty fast compared to other math typesetting libraries!
Today, as I was doing some math on my blog, I realize that inline math was not rendered. At first I thought that this was a conflict between KaTeX and goldmark but actually, I needed to tweak the delimiters KaTeX option.</description></item><item><title>Let AppVeyor watch inSileco!</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2018/10/2018-10-02_let_appveyor_watch/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2018/10/2018-10-02_let_appveyor_watch/</guid><description>I very much enjoy sharing thoughts and code on our blog inSileco. Recently, one of the authors mentioned that he was not able to clone the repository on his Windows machine. I came to realize that we better not assume that everybody is working on MacOS or Linux and check that inSileco works well on Windows. One of the most convenient way to do so is to use AppVeyor and I therefore decided to spend some time making the build passed on AppVeyor!</description></item><item><title>My Hugo shortcode for video</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2018/09/2018-09-27_my_hugo_shortcode/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2018/09/2018-09-27_my_hugo_shortcode/</guid><description>Shortcodes are among my favorite features in Hugo. As I am currently writing several notes a week that often include small screencasts, I thought that the time had come for me to create my own screencast shortcode. Here it is:
1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 &amp;lt;center&amp;gt; &amp;lt;video width=&amp;#39; {{ if .Get &amp;#34;width&amp;#34; }} {{ .Get &amp;#34;width&amp;#34; }} {{ else }} 100% {{ end }}&amp;#39; controls&amp;gt; &amp;lt;source src=&amp;#34;{{ .</description></item></channel></rss>