<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Release on KevCaz's Website</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/tags/release/</link><description>Recent content in Release on KevCaz's Website</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Content under CC0 1.0 Universal unless otherwise specified.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://kevcaz.github.io/tags/release/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>From Mantic Minotaur to Noble Numbat</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2024/05/2024-05-30_noble_numbat/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2024/05/2024-05-30_noble_numbat/</guid><description>Screenshot of my current desktop wallpaper, Little numbat boy by @azskalt, see The Coronation of a New Mascot: Noble Numbat. After a freezing phase that started last March, Ubuntu 24.04 codenamed Noble Numbat was released last April. It comes with a great deal of new features, listed in the release release notes.
As a Mantic Minotaur user, the option to update to Noble Numbat was presented in May, in a window that popped up after a regular update.</description></item><item><title>From Lunar Lobster to Mantic Minotaur</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2023/11/2023-11-05_from_lunar_lobster/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2023/11/2023-11-05_from_lunar_lobster/</guid><description>I have recently decided to upgrade to the most recent Ubuntu release on my Dell Precision machine, in other words, I wanted to get closer to Ubuntu&amp;rsquo;s release cycle. Previously, I would reinstall the latest long time release (LTS) every time a new update pops up (see the documentation). About 3 months ago, I switched to Ubuntu 23.04 (Lunar Lobster) and yesterday I upgraded to the October&amp;rsquo;s release, Mantic Minotaur (23.</description></item><item><title>From Bullseye to Bookworm</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2021/08/2021-08-29_from_bullseye_to/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2021/08/2021-08-29_from_bullseye_to/</guid><description>Two weeks ago, Bullseye became the new stable Debian release. As I prefer using Debian testing, today, I jumped on Debian 12 codenamed Bookworm. To do so, I simply updated my source list by replacing instances of bullseye by bookworm, and then I used the combo apt update/ apt upgrade.
1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 17 18 19 20 $ apt-get update [.</description></item><item><title>Debian 10 *buster* released</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2019/07/2019-07-09_debian_10_buster/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2019/07/2019-07-09_debian_10_buster/</guid><description>I have been on Debian buster for more than a year while it was the Debian Testing. After a frozen period that lasted a few months, buster is the new stable Debian distribution since yesterday!
What does this change on my end? Not much! Basically, as I was already using buster in my /etc/apt/sources.list.d/ file, when I used apt-get update I got the following message:
1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 Get:1 http://security.</description></item></channel></rss>