<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>gnome-terminal on KevCaz's Website</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/tags/gnome-terminal/</link><description>Recent content in gnome-terminal on KevCaz's Website</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Content under CC0 1.0 Universal unless otherwise specified.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://kevcaz.github.io/tags/gnome-terminal/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Use Gogh to color your terminal!</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/cli/usegogh/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/cli/usegogh/</guid><description>As mentioned in a previous note, I now use Atom together with Gnome Terminal for most of my coding and writing time and really enjoy my current setup. As I use two different applications, I have similar but slightly different color schemes, which, weirdly enough, has been bugging me for a while&amp;hellip; That is why, a few days ago, I started to edit the color but looking a the them repository of the Atom theme I liked (e.</description></item><item><title>Send a set of command lines to GNOME Terminal</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/cli/paste2gnuterm/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/cli/paste2gnuterm/</guid><description>Context As mentioned several times on this website, I use Atom for my coding as well as for writing posts and manuscripts. While coding, one often needs to run commands in a terminal. To do so, I use specific Atom packages such as IDE-R or Julia Client to run R and Julia commands respectively and platformio-ide-terminal. The latter meets most of my expectations, but:
the terminal emulated is in a bottom panel and when I&amp;rsquo;m working on my laptop I cannot get a good overview of the code and the corresponding outputs at the same time, pretty annoying&amp;hellip; and having the terminal in the right panel is a feature unlikely to be implemented in a near future;</description></item></channel></rss>