<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>KevCaz's Website</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/</link><description>Recent content on KevCaz's Website</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Content under CC0 1.0 Universal unless otherwise specified.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://kevcaz.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Generating subtitles with `auto_subtitle`</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2024/07/2024-07-25_autosubtitle/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2024/07/2024-07-25_autosubtitle/</guid><description>I was recently trying to obtain subtitles for a video in Spanish. For numerous movies and TV shows, it is relatively easy to find subtitles files online (mainly as .srt files, i.e. SubRip files), but that is not true for all contents!
When I thought about automating the generation of subtitles for a minute, I was convinced that with a tool to extract the audio from a movie file and a trained AI model that would generate the transcript, it should be doable to automate the process.</description></item><item><title>From Mantic Minotaur to Noble Numbat</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2024/05/2024-05-30_noble_numbat/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2024/05/2024-05-30_noble_numbat/</guid><description>Screenshot of my current desktop wallpaper, Little numbat boy by @azskalt, see The Coronation of a New Mascot: Noble Numbat. After a freezing phase that started last March, Ubuntu 24.04 codenamed Noble Numbat was released last April. It comes with a great deal of new features, listed in the release release notes.
As a Mantic Minotaur user, the option to update to Noble Numbat was presented in May, in a window that popped up after a regular update.</description></item><item><title>A new tree file for my notes</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2024/03/2023-03-07_a_new_tree/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2024/03/2023-03-07_a_new_tree/</guid><description>Context This section of my website is where I jot down notes that will be useful to my future self and hopefully to others. For years my notes have been organized into a set of folders that serve as categories that I thought were relevant. After 5 years and &amp;gt;120 notes, I realized that the categories were somewhat contrived (e.g. cli, linux), and that it was hard to locate a post and the assets were now managed consistently.</description></item><item><title>Reading 'The Linux command line' - Part I</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2024/03/2024-03-04_reading_the_linux/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2024/03/2024-03-04_reading_the_linux/</guid><description>I have been using the command line for more than 10 years now, I started on MacOS1 and I increased my usage of the Terminal when I switched to Linux. I am now comfortable with the Linux command line but still looking for ways to improve my skills. Recently, I stumbled into no starch press that offers a great selection of books and found out that several are available at the library.</description></item><item><title>From Lunar Lobster to Mantic Minotaur</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2023/11/2023-11-05_from_lunar_lobster/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2023/11/2023-11-05_from_lunar_lobster/</guid><description>I have recently decided to upgrade to the most recent Ubuntu release on my Dell Precision machine, in other words, I wanted to get closer to Ubuntu&amp;rsquo;s release cycle. Previously, I would reinstall the latest long time release (LTS) every time a new update pops up (see the documentation). About 3 months ago, I switched to Ubuntu 23.04 (Lunar Lobster) and yesterday I upgraded to the October&amp;rsquo;s release, Mantic Minotaur (23.</description></item><item><title>Some Julia language elements to keep in mind</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2023/08/2023-08-16_some_julia_language/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2023/08/2023-08-16_some_julia_language/</guid><description>As I am jumping on a project where I will code mainly in Julia, I thought it was worth spending some time to remind myself about core Julia&amp;rsquo;s features. I have already spent some reading reading Julia&amp;rsquo;s documentation which is great and definitively worth reading, but I was looking for something shorter and found &amp;lsquo;Julia language: a concise tutorial&amp;rsquo; (Github repository available here), which by the way is listed in the Julia tutorials page.</description></item><item><title>Installing Python packages in Debian Trixie</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2023/08/2023-08-10_installing_python_packages/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2023/08/2023-08-10_installing_python_packages/</guid><description>I recently switched back to Debian testing and since last June, testing is Debian 13 (codename Trixie). As I was installing a bunch of Python packages, I got the following error:
1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 17 18 19 20 21 22 23 $ pip install numpy error: externally-managed-environment × This environment is externally managed ╰─&amp;gt; To install Python packages system-wide, try apt install python3-xyz, where xyz is the package you are trying to install.</description></item><item><title>Ansible playbook for setting up Nextcloud on a Raspberry Pi 3B</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2023/04/2023-04-23_ansible_playbook_for/</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2023/04/2023-04-23_ansible_playbook_for/</guid><description>I recently got a new SD card for my Raspberry Pi 3B, so I had to reinstall Nextcloud and I took the opportunity to create an Ansible playbook for it. I basically went through the steps described in my previous note &amp;lsquo;Nextcloud server on a Raspberry Pi 3B&amp;rsquo; and I turned them into a playbook. If you want to get an idea of what is Ansible, check out the Wikipedia article and for what follows, let&amp;rsquo;s keep in mind the following:</description></item><item><title>Lack of boot space</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2023/03/2023-03-23_lack_of_boot/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2023/03/2023-03-23_lack_of_boot/</guid><description>On my Ubuntu 20.04 device at work, I ran into the same issue several times. Basically, I was not able to install the latest kernel because I was running out of boot space. As it turned out, the previous kernel images were kept and as I had only 700 Mb of boot space (/boot partition), after stacking a few images (most of them were OEM kernels) I was not able to update the kernel.</description></item><item><title>rcites 1.3.0</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2023/02/2023-02-19_rcites_1_3/</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2023/02/2023-02-19_rcites_1_3/</guid><description>rcites 1.3.0 is now available on CRAN &amp;#x1f389;. This was mainly a maintenance release following up on a recent issue in vcr (see Overview of fixes for upcoming v1.2) but I also took the opportunity to improve the set_token() function. Now the user has up to five attempts to set up the token when set_token() is called, after that error is triggered (previously the error was triggered after the first failed attempt).</description></item><item><title>Debian Bookworm setup -- update</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2023/02/2023-02-03_debian_bookworm_setup/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2023/02/2023-02-03_debian_bookworm_setup/</guid><description>I recently lent someone my Lenovo T470p and when I got it back, I decided to install Debian back on it (I installed Ubuntu 22.04 to make it easier to use for a non-Linux user). I went through all the installation seamlessly, but I was not able to have the wifi working. I knew it was related to firmware-iwlwifi, but I was unable to install it. As it turned out, the package was not available for bookworm (found this but looking at https://packages.</description></item><item><title>rmangal 2.1.2</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2023/01/2023-01-31_rmangal_2_1/</link><pubDate>Tue, 31 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2023/01/2023-01-31_rmangal_2_1/</guid><description>A new release of rmangal is now available on CRAN. Following up on a recent issue in vcr (see ' Overview of fixes for upcoming v1.2&amp;rsquo; for more details), I decided to have fixtures written in JSON rather than in YAML, the change was pretty straightforward
1 2 3 4 5 6 7 # see tests/testthat/setup-rmangal.R # in https://github.com/ropensci/rmangal/commit/9a2293d75b8af7f4b856e024dc8760f97d349e50#diff-ab9aa624c8da203a8b11856c8203c5de205fa4cabceb048838c965106a3d406f vcr::vcr_configure( dir = &amp;#34;../fixtures&amp;#34;, write_disk_path = &amp;#34;../files&amp;#34;, serialize_with = &amp;#34;json&amp;#34; ) instead of</description></item><item><title>Debian Bookworm setup</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2022/05/2022-05-22_debian_bookworm_setup/</link><pubDate>Sun, 22 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2022/05/2022-05-22_debian_bookworm_setup/</guid><description>I recently decided to re-install my computer and I took the opportunity to create a gist that includes light version of my Debian 11 set-up, i.e. all the tools I used the most. Once again during the install (I use a Debian weekly build installation image) did not keep things light as I let several pieces of software be installed during the setup (e.g. LibreOffice, Inkscape). So here goes the 4th version of my bash script to install Debian on my Lenovo T470p &amp;#x2b07;&amp;#xfe0f;.</description></item><item><title>Basic Git server on my Raspberry Pi</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2022/01/2022-01-11_basic_git_server/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2022/01/2022-01-11_basic_git_server/</guid><description>As mentioned in my previous post, I have recently started using my Raspberry Pi as a server and I decided to try to host a basic Git server.
As explained in the chapter &amp;ldquo;Git on the Server&amp;rdquo; of Pro Git1, among other protocols, Git supports SSH and it is quite straightforward to setup a basic Git server via this protocol. As I can access my Raspberry Pi via ssh, I decided to give it a try!</description></item><item><title>Nextcloud server on a Raspberry Pi 3B</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2022/01/2022-01-05_nextcloud_server_on/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2022/01/2022-01-05_nextcloud_server_on/</guid><description>I have already written elsewhere all the good that I think about Raspberry Pi. It is a fantastic project supported by a great community. I personally own a Rapsberry Pi model 3B and so far I have been using it for several small projects. For more than a year I have been thinking about running some small services on my Raspberry Pi, but never took the time to set it up.</description></item><item><title>Releasing the research compendium for our Labmnivory paper</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/econotes/2021/publish_compendium/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/econotes/2021/publish_compendium/</guid><description>&amp;#x1f4e3; This post was first published on mccannlab.ca. Good news everyone! This week, our &amp;ldquo;Labmnivory&amp;rdquo; paper led by Marie Gutgesell has been accepted in Bioscience. Therefore, the time has come to release the code we promised explicitly in the manuscript.
Code for theoretical investigations will be made available on GitHub and archive on Zenodo upon manuscript acceptance.
For reproducibility&amp;rsquo;s sake, we&amp;rsquo;ve structured our Julia scripts as a research compendium which so far has been hosted on GitHub, in a private repository.</description></item><item><title>Converting svg to eps with Inkscape cli</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2021/12/2021-12-06_converting_svg_to/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2021/12/2021-12-06_converting_svg_to/</guid><description>&amp;#x23e9; tl;dr: You can convert your SVG file myfig.sv to EPS using inkscape myfig.svg -o myfig.eps --export-ps-level=3.
The problem For the latest paper we&amp;rsquo;ve submitted, the journal required figures in EPS, but all the figures I&amp;rsquo;ve had created were in SVG. That really puzzled me! Why on earth forcing authors to submit in EPS? At the very least the journal policy should allow authors to submit in other vector formats&amp;hellip; I actually think this is rather problematic because 1.</description></item><item><title>R packages rmangal and rcites updated on CRAN</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2021/11/2021-11-25_r_packages_rmangal/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2021/11/2021-11-25_r_packages_rmangal/</guid><description>Over the past few weeks, I took some time to review the unit tests for rmangal and rcites. Both packages are R clients for web APIs:
rmangal allows users to search ecological interactions available in the Mangal database; rcites allows users to query the Species+ database by leveraging the Speciesplus/CITES Checklist API. One of the main challenges with such packages is to not get archived on CRAN &amp;#x1f631;! rmangal was actually archived a year ago for policy violation on internet access, and so one of my main goals was to get it back on CRAN.</description></item><item><title>Matplotlib could not be imported by pyimport `[SOLVED]`</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2021/11/2021-11-23_matplotlib_could_not/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2021/11/2021-11-23_matplotlib_could_not/</guid><description>I have been experiencing an issue following a recent Python update. Basically, when I was trying to use PyPlot, I got the following message error.
1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 17 18 19 20 21 22 23 24 25 26 27 28 29 30 31 32 33 34 35 36 37 38 39 40 41 42 43 44 45 46 47 48 49 50 51 52 53 54 55 56 julia&amp;gt; using PyPlot ERROR: InitError: PyError (PyImport_ImportModule The Python package matplotlib could not be imported by pyimport.</description></item><item><title>Officiel</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/perso/famille/officiel/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/perso/famille/officiel/</guid><description/></item><item><title>I think I have finally found the right tool to manage my todo lists</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2021/11/2021-11-21_i_think_i/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2021/11/2021-11-21_i_think_i/</guid><description>I do some efforts to be somewhat organized, but I tend to rely way too much on my memory and give too much importance to my mood when it comes to decide what work I need to do first. Over the last 2 or 3 years I have become more and more aware of this and I have realized that this affects my productivity. My goal is not to be as productive as I can but still, if I can achieve more work in less time at my work, it means that I can spend more time on doing something else than working&amp;hellip; which is basically the reason why I have been looking for tools to help me get more organized.</description></item><item><title>LA GUERRE DES METAUX RARES `[LIVRE]`</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/perso/opinions/2021/metauxrares/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/perso/opinions/2021/metauxrares/</guid><description>Couverture de l&amp;rsquo;édition de poche de La guerre des métaux rares de Guillaume Pitron paru le 10/01/2018 aux éditions Les liens qui libèrent (ISBN : 979-10-209-0574-1). Opinion C&amp;rsquo;est à la suite de la passionnante entrevue de l&amp;rsquo;auteur sur la chaîne Youtube Thinkerview que je me suis convaincu de lire cet ouvrage, et le hasard faisant bien les choses, je suis tombé sur un exemplaire de l&amp;rsquo;édition de poche dans une boutique de livres usagés!</description></item><item><title>Give schemacrawler a go!</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2021/09/2021-09-17_give_schemacrawler_a/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2021/09/2021-09-17_give_schemacrawler_a/</guid><description>Few months ago, I was looking for a way to check the evolution of the structure of one SQLite database I am working on, so I thought having a simple way to get a schema of my database would be a simple solution. A colleague of mine suggested to give SchemaCrawler a try, and so I gave it a go.
I quickly realized that the easiest way to use it on my Debian machine was to use the Docker image, and so I did</description></item><item><title>Convert bibtex file to YAML with pandoc</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2021/09/2021-09-02_convert_bibtex_file/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2021/09/2021-09-02_convert_bibtex_file/</guid><description>When I need to update my publication list, I usually retrieve a bibtex file (.bib) from OrcID. I used to convert this file into a YAML with pandoc-citeproc like this
1 $ pandoc-citeproc --bib2yaml pubs.bib &amp;gt; pubs.yaml Since pandoc 2.11, pandoc-citeproc is no longer used to format citations and the repository is now archived:
Pandoc now uses the citeproc library, and no external filter is needed.
So I decided to give it a try and adjust some scripts of my own using the new way of doing the conversion.</description></item><item><title>From Bullseye to Bookworm</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2021/08/2021-08-29_from_bullseye_to/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2021/08/2021-08-29_from_bullseye_to/</guid><description>Two weeks ago, Bullseye became the new stable Debian release. As I prefer using Debian testing, today, I jumped on Debian 12 codenamed Bookworm. To do so, I simply updated my source list by replacing instances of bullseye by bookworm, and then I used the combo apt update/ apt upgrade.
1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 17 18 19 20 $ apt-get update [.</description></item><item><title>On the sensitivity of food webs to multiple stressors</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/econotes/2021/mulistressors/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/econotes/2021/mulistressors/</guid><description>Our latest work1 led by David Beauchesne is out since yesterday in Ecology Letters &amp;#x1f973;! This paper introduces a framework that allows the exploration of the impact of multiple stressors on food webs.
In the Anthropocene, human activities impact species is various ways. Multiple stressors frameworks attempt to account for their diversity and their joint effects (stressors may have antagonistic or synergistic effects). Most of such frameworks (if not all) are species-based, meaning that they account for the sensitivity of species to the stressors and the intensity of the stressor (e.</description></item><item><title>The Thunderbird Debian package has already been patched!</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2021/06/2021-06-30_the_thunderbird_debian/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2021/06/2021-06-30_the_thunderbird_debian/</guid><description>In my previous note, I reported major issues with Thunderbird 78.11.0-1. As it turned out, it was an actual bug that has been reported. Shortly after the report, a work around has been proposed, and the new patch uploaded last Sunday (2021/06/29) solves all the issues I encountered. So everything is back to normal!
1 2 3 4 5 6 $ apt-cache show thunderbird | head -n 5 Package: thunderbird Version: 1:78.</description></item><item><title>What is wrong with Thunderbird?</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2021/06/2021-06-19_what_is_wrong/</link><pubDate>Sat, 19 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2021/06/2021-06-19_what_is_wrong/</guid><description>Few days ago, as I was trying to refresh my emails, I realize that Thunderbird (Thunderbird 78.11.0) was no longer able to retrieved my mails from Gmail. I tried to understand what was the problem but I wasn&amp;rsquo;t able to figure it out. After a while, I decided to uninstall Thunderbird and reinstall it. Things just got worst I couldn&amp;rsquo;t set any of my email accounts. For my Gmail, I tried to use OAuth2, as it is recommended (it used to work for me), but the identification protocol did not work: instead of getting the Gmail interface to login, I got an error message pointing out a lack of security (NS_ERROR_NET_INADEQUATE_SECURITY)&amp;hellip; As I did not understand why, I decided to stop speeding time on trying to find the origin of the problem.</description></item><item><title>Corals, Algae, Fish and Humans</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/econotes/2021/corals/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/econotes/2021/corals/</guid><description>As I am jumping into a new project on coral reefs in the Carribeans, I thought it would make great sense for me to spend some time to get some basic ideas about corals, what&amp;rsquo;s currently threatening them and what are the consequences of the worldwide decline of coral cover.
Some basic knowledge about corals Corals are cnidarians, Cnidaria is a phylum that includes hydrae (Hydrozoa), jellyfish (Medusozoa), among others. Corals form colonies made of clones called polyps that are linked by a tissue called coenenchyme1.</description></item><item><title>The Pragmatic Programmer</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2021/06/2021-06-11_the_pragmatic_programmer/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2021/06/2021-06-11_the_pragmatic_programmer/</guid><description>The Pragmatic Programmer, book cover of the 20th Anniversary Edition. I have been meaning to read it for at least 5 years and I am very happy I finally took the time to read The Pragmatic Programmer, a book regarded as one of most influential among software engineers. As it turned out, it was a good thing to wait those 5 years because since the authors have released a new edition in 2020, for the 20th anniversary of the book.</description></item><item><title>Use flatpak!</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2021/02/2021-02-10_use_flatpak/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2021/02/2021-02-10_use_flatpak/</guid><description>Two days ago, I was attempting to install GNOME Fractal but apt-get couldn&amp;rsquo;t find it&amp;hellip; Cause it&amp;rsquo;s a GNOME application I thought is was unexpected, so I checked the README file. It turned out that the developers actually suggest to install their app with either Snap or Flatpak. As I knew about the former and hadn&amp;rsquo;t heard about the later, I decided to install flatpak.
1 $ apt install flatpak I then used flatpak to install Fractal.</description></item><item><title>Writing your emails in Markdown with Thunderbird 78</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2021/01/2021-01-31_writing_your_emails/</link><pubDate>Sun, 31 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2021/01/2021-01-31_writing_your_emails/</guid><description>For more than three years now, I have been written most of my emails in Markdown! How so? I have been using the Markdown Here add-on for Thunderbird. As explained in the &amp;lsquo;features&amp;rsquo; page of the extension website:
Markdown Here is an extension for Chrome, Firefox, Safari, Opera, Thunderbird, and Postbox. With it, you can write email in Markdown, and then click a button (or context menu item, or use a hotkey) to render the email into good-looking, fully formatted text (HTML, technically).</description></item><item><title>Time to talk about this website!</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2021/01/2021-01-29_time_to_talk/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2021/01/2021-01-29_time_to_talk/</guid><description>For this 100th SilicoNote/post, I have decided to share some notes about this website : its story and a few details about how I built the last version of it.
The short story behind my website As far as I remembered, I have built 5 different versions of my personal website. I decided to get a website when I was doing my PhD, back in 2014 (not a 100% about sure about the timeline), in order to share some of my work.</description></item><item><title>Concatenate audio files with FFmpeg</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2020/10/2020-10-24_concatenate_audio_files/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2020/10/2020-10-24_concatenate_audio_files/</guid><description>Yesterday I needed to combine several audio files and I figured out to do this with command lines. It was not as easy as I expected but I guess I underestimated how little I know about audio files! Anyway, below I explain what I did!
Preparing my audio files I had several audio files that I recorded with the voice recorder available on my phone. This application saves audio files as .</description></item><item><title>Quatrain 004</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/perso/opinions/2020/quatrain004/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/perso/opinions/2020/quatrain004/</guid><description>Octobre vert jaune rouge Rouge, jaune et encore un soupçon de vert, Au revoir l&amp;rsquo;été, à bientôt l’hiver,
Les forêts s&amp;rsquo;illuminent et on s&amp;rsquo;étonne,
Qu&amp;rsquo;elles soient si belles, les couleurs de l&amp;rsquo;automne.</description></item><item><title>Quatrain 003</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/perso/opinions/2020/quatrain003/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/perso/opinions/2020/quatrain003/</guid><description>Complisilicité Tous les deux mus par l&amp;rsquo;autre, mais quelle relation! De nos regards, une intensité, un émoi,
C&amp;rsquo;est l&amp;rsquo;intrication de nos imaginations, Deux êtres inséparables, mon écran et moi.</description></item><item><title>Quatrain 002</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/perso/opinions/2020/quatrain002/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/perso/opinions/2020/quatrain002/</guid><description>Onirisme silicieux Un pas en avant, deux pas en arrière,
Le progrès suit un bien triste chemin, La gloire au béton, l&amp;rsquo;oubli aux tourbières,
Le minéral chante nos lendemains.</description></item><item><title>Quatrain 001</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/perso/opinions/2020/quatrain001/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/perso/opinions/2020/quatrain001/</guid><description>Le Credo du crédule Sur un tas de on-dit, bâtis des théories,
Négliges l&amp;rsquo;élégance, privilégies l&amp;rsquo;outrance, Ignores les faits précis, ne crains point l&amp;rsquo;aporie,
Puisque leurs vraisemblances, n&amp;rsquo;ont aucune importance.</description></item><item><title>Installing Spell Right on VSCodium v1.49</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2020/09/2020-09-21_installing_spell_right/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2020/09/2020-09-21_installing_spell_right/</guid><description>VSCodium is an automatic &amp;ldquo;clean&amp;rdquo; build of Virtual Studio Code (VSCode), i.e. a build without the Microsoft touch. VSCode (thus VSCodium) is very powerful, has a tons of features and its development is very dynamic, so I am always keeping an eye on what&amp;rsquo;s new with VSCode even though I am still using Atom more frequently.
When I set up Bullseye on my ThinkPad I installed the latest version of VSCodium and when I looked up for my favorite extensions, I realized that many extensions were actually missing.</description></item><item><title>Migrating from Buster to Bullseye</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2020/09/2020-09-18_migrating_from_buster/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2020/09/2020-09-18_migrating_from_buster/</guid><description>In July 2019, Buster became the stable release of Debian and the Bullseye became de facto the new testing distribution. After spending almost 2 years on Buster, I decided last week that it was time to migrate to Bullseye.
Backing up I frequently backup my files (so far with a simple bash function that copies them to my external hard drive). Plus, I also have a repository, dotfiles, where I stored my configuration files (the ones I can share).</description></item><item><title>Renaming files with `mv`, `rename` and `R`</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2020/09/2020-09-08_renaming_files_with/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2020/09/2020-09-08_renaming_files_with/</guid><description>For a project I have been working on for quite some time now, I ended up handling thousands of files and as I initially named them poorly, I had to rename a bunch of them&amp;hellip; Basically, I needed to do two kind of file name manipulations.
problem 1 is kind of trivial : replacing the same part of the file names by another, e.g. renaming res_old1_001.txt, res_old1_002.txt, &amp;hellip;, res_old1_010.txt to res_new2_001.</description></item><item><title>Running parallel simulations with scripts that take two or more varying parameters</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2020/08/2020-08-20_running_parallel_simulations/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2020/08/2020-08-20_running_parallel_simulations/</guid><description>Another note about how I work with Slurm! Today, I comment on three strategies to run simulations for which the values taken by two arguments (or more) vary from one simulation to another.
The problem Let&amp;rsquo;s assume that we run simulations by calling a Julia script myscript.jl that takes p1 as argument, in order to run the simulation on one CPU for a single simulation, I would run the following bas command</description></item><item><title>Co-occurrence, not interaction!</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/econotes/2020/coocnotinter/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/econotes/2020/coocnotinter/</guid><description>This note is a short comment on the paper Guillaume Blanchet, Dominique Gravel and I recently published in Ecology Letters.
What information is contained in co-occurrence data? I don&amp;#39;t have a definitive answer to this question but assuming co-occurrence data are proxies for ecological interactions could lead to erroneous conclusions, we explain why in this new piece https://t.co/Ze9o7pfZNF
&amp;mdash; Kevin Cazelles (@KCazelles) May 20, 2020 What did we do? We basically went over 7 arguments to explain why the information in co-occurrence cannot be taken as a proxy for ecological interactions.</description></item><item><title>Beware of `apply()` outputs!</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2020/07/2020-07-01_beware_of_apply/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2020/07/2020-07-01_beware_of_apply/</guid><description>I have been frequently using apply() for years now, quite happily. But yesterday, I was surprised by how apply() works and in this note I&amp;rsquo;ll try to explaining why.
Let&amp;rsquo;s consider the following data frame.
1 R&amp;gt; df0 &amp;lt;- data.frame(v1 = letters[1:3], v2 = 1:3) And let&amp;rsquo;s assume I need to convert all columns, irrespective of their class, to columns of character strings (this example is somewhat contrived, but illustrates well the issue).</description></item><item><title>Array job with Slurm: a use case and a mistake I made!</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2020/06/2020-06-19_array_job_with/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2020/06/2020-06-19_array_job_with/</guid><description>&amp;#x26a0;&amp;#xfe0f; I won&amp;rsquo;t introduce Slurm here as I already have written several notes about it (see the Slurm tag).
Today, I needed to send 171 jobs to the server. All jobs were similar similar, only the species ID was changing, exactly the kind of computation array jobs were designed for. As there are 32 cpus per nodes, I figured I needed 6 nodes. And so I wrote the following bash script:</description></item><item><title>Never too late to publish your code!</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/econotes/2020/biogeonet/</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/econotes/2020/biogeonet/</guid><description>Since 2017, for every article I work on, I now do my best to release the code I used to obtain the results presented therein (see my research compendia in the software section). In my humble opinion, this is the least I can do cause the numerical part of a study (often a large part of my work) is relatively easy to reproduce, though it requires some time to master the tools to do so.</description></item><item><title>Submitting a Julia script with Slurm</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2020/05/2020-05-01_submitting_a_julia/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2020/05/2020-05-01_submitting_a_julia/</guid><description>In a previous note, I&amp;rsquo;ve narrated my transition from Mammoth to Graham and I&amp;rsquo;ve exemplified how to submit an job with Slurm. As I&amp;rsquo;m currently using Julia for several projects, I&amp;rsquo;d like to report how I submitted my Julia script to the scheduler.
First of all, I needed to set up Julia for my account. As Graham runs under CentOS and as I had already loaded Julia v1.3.11, I just had to update the version of Julia with module.</description></item><item><title>Inline Math with KaTeX</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2020/04/2020-04-19_inline_math_with/</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2020/04/2020-04-19_inline_math_with/</guid><description>For this blog, I am currently using Hugo v0.62.2, and since v0.60 Hugo by default, goldmark is used under the hood to render Markdown to HTML. Moreover, to write math I am now using Katex which is pretty fast compared to other math typesetting libraries!
Today, as I was doing some math on my blog, I realize that inline math was not rendered. At first I thought that this was a conflict between KaTeX and goldmark but actually, I needed to tweak the delimiters KaTeX option.</description></item><item><title>Deploy a pkgdown website on gh-pages manually</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2020/04/2020-04-12_deploy_a_pkgdown/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2020/04/2020-04-12_deploy_a_pkgdown/</guid><description>This is another note about deploying a pkgdown1 website with Travis on gh-pages. I had previously used the package travis but I was recently interested in doing so manually. Fortunately, I found this very helpful walk-through by Gábor Csárdi2. I used it and it worked well for a while, but at some point I had an issue with the deployment part (still not sure why), so I changed it. Instead of using the following config3</description></item><item><title>Generate a ssh key with R</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2020/04/2020-04-04_generate_a_ssh/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2020/04/2020-04-04_generate_a_ssh/</guid><description>I now frequently use GitHub actions to deploy websites on gh-pages. One way to do so requires to use a ssh key (the full procedure is well explained, inter alia, in the README of peaceiris/actions-gh-pages). As I am used to work with the Terminal, when I need such a key, I use the following command line:
1 $ ssh-keygen -t rsa -b 4096 -C &amp;#34;$(git config user.email)&amp;#34; -f gh-pages -N &amp;#34;&amp;#34; which generates two files:</description></item><item><title>Fill out your XFA forms with Master PDF</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2020/03/2020-03-25_fill_out_your/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2020/03/2020-03-25_fill_out_your/</guid><description>The other day I needed to fill out some XFA forms. On the website I was told to use Acrobat Reader &amp;#x1f628;&amp;hellip; which is not supported on Linux. So I looked for an alternative to work on Debian 10, when I stumbled into this answer on mentioning Master PDF, so I installed it:
1 $ apt-get install master-pdf-editor and you know what? Worked like a charm! &amp;#x1f386;</description></item><item><title>Count your lines of code with `cloc`</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2020/02/2020-02-09_count_your_lines/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2020/02/2020-02-09_count_your_lines/</guid><description>I recently found out about cloc that is a very useful command line tool written in Perl that &amp;ldquo;counts blank lines, comment lines, and physical lines of source code in many programming languages&amp;rdquo;1. Let&amp;rsquo;s see how it works 👁.
The first step is to install cloc, there are several ways to do so, as a Debian user (Debian Buster) all I had to do was to use apt-get:
1 $ apt-get install cloc Once installed, cloc can be call in a Terminal like so: cloc path/to/file_or_folder.</description></item><item><title>GitHub pages &amp; custom domain name? Don't forget CNAME! `[SOLVED]`</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2020/02/2020-02-04_github_pages_custom/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2020/02/2020-02-04_github_pages_custom/</guid><description>The problem ❔ I am maintaining the website of the McCann Lab that is currently hosted on the GitHub Pages. Since I set up the custom domain, I was experiencing a weird issue: after every single deployment even on GitHub Pages (originally done by Travis, now by using a dedicated GitHub Actions workflow) the custom domain was removed and I had to rewrite it every time (see &amp;#x2b07;&amp;#xfe0f;) which was pretty annoying.</description></item><item><title>Brexit!</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/perso/opinions/2020/brexit/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/perso/opinions/2020/brexit/</guid><description>Après le référendum du 23 juin 2016 (initié par David Cameron et quelques 3 ans ½ chaotiques à se demander quand l&amp;rsquo;Union Européenne (UE) et Le Royaume-Uni (RU) trouveraient un accord sur le Brexit et même, parfois, si un nouveau référendum aurait lieu), les résultats aux législatives de décembre dernier ont mis fin au suspens et le divorce a été prononcé le 31 janvier 2020 à 23h GMT. A titre personnel, je regrette sincèrement cet évènement car il me semble que la période actuelle, faite de tensions géopolitiques majeures et de bouleversements environnementaux sans précédent, demande une Europe forte, soudée, capable de peser dans les décisions internationales.</description></item><item><title>Updating all your Python packages</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2020/01/2020-01-05_updating_all_your/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2020/01/2020-01-05_updating_all_your/</guid><description>Even if I do not frequently code in Python, my setup includes several packages of this programming language. While I was looking for a simple way to update all installed packages, I found this thread on stack overflow which helps me writing the following alias in my zsh profile:
1 2 3 alias updpy=&amp;#39;for i in $(pip list --outdated --format=columns |tail -n +3|cut -d&amp;#34; &amp;#34; -f1) do pip install --user $i --upgrade done&amp;#39; Now, when I enter updpy in my Terminal, all installed Python packages are updated.</description></item><item><title>GitHub actions, checkout and submodule</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2019/12/2019-12-04_github_actions_checkout/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2019/12/2019-12-04_github_actions_checkout/</guid><description>I now use GitHub Actions to deploy this website (see my previous note about it) and last Monday (two days ago &amp;#x1f603;) after I pushed I got an email saying the deployment failed and found the following error message in the console log:
1 ##[error]The input &amp;#39;submodules&amp;#39; is not supported in actions/checkout@v2 Turns out this is because version 2 of checkout does not support submodule yet (see this issue report https://github.</description></item><item><title>Color and rotate an image with ImageMagick</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2019/12/2019-12-02_color_and_rotate/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2019/12/2019-12-02_color_and_rotate/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve already written about ImageMagick in previous notes (e.g. this one about image resizing). Yesterday I used convert to color and rotate an image and I would like to show how simple it is here. Note that in order to show what the different command lines yield, I&amp;rsquo;ve used the PNG file of the GitHub Octocat (Octocat.png) available at https://github.com/logos.
Octocat.png To fill Octocat.png with black, I&amp;rsquo;ve used the following command line:</description></item><item><title>Noël 2019</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/perso/famille/noel_2019/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/perso/famille/noel_2019/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Metro, boulot, jeu de mots!</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/perso/famille/metroboulotjeudmots/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/perso/famille/metroboulotjeudmots/</guid><description>C&amp;rsquo;est en compagnie de Maître Zgirski et du Professeur Legagneux que j&amp;rsquo;ai pris la ligne 1 lundi matin. Avec un rendez-vous à 9h à l&amp;rsquo;université de McGill en partant de Sauvé, nous eûmes la joie d&amp;rsquo;expérimenter l&amp;rsquo;heure de pointe du métro Montréalais. Avec le défilement des stations, la compaction dans le wagon s’accrut et la proximité exagérée avec de parfaits étrangers nous rapprocha tranquillement du plan de ce dernier. En observant attentivement les noms des stations fort bien agencés, nous pûmes attester d&amp;rsquo;une belle diversité de sonorité.</description></item><item><title>My first workflow with GitHub Actions</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2019/11/2019-11-20_my_first_workflow/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2019/11/2019-11-20_my_first_workflow/</guid><description>As explained on GitHub:
GitHub Actions makes it easy to automate all your software workflows, now with world-class CI/CD. Build, test, and deploy your code right from GitHub. Make code reviews, branch management, and issue triaging work the way you want.
I&amp;rsquo;ve heard about this feature and I decided to give it a first go yesterday as I wanted to deploy a notebook for the McCann Lab&amp;rsquo;s Theory Club built with bookdown.</description></item><item><title>Markdown tables to Word tables `[WORK AROUND]`</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2019/11/2019-11-18_markdown_tables_to/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2019/11/2019-11-18_markdown_tables_to/</guid><description>Pandoc is an amazing document converter that I use very frequently. Earlier today, as I was converting a Markdown document (.md) to a Word one (.docx) I realized that the tables weren&amp;rsquo;t rendered properly. More precisely, after opening the document with LibreOffice, the first column of every tables was using the full width of the document and I was not able to quickly fix this issue with LibreOffice. I figured that this was caused by either pandoc or LibreOffice and so I first checked the version of pandoc installed:</description></item><item><title>Combining Slurm and GNU parallel</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2019/11/2019-11-11_combining_slurm_and/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2019/11/2019-11-11_combining_slurm_and/</guid><description>Last week, I attended a &amp;ldquo;Midi conférence&amp;rdquo; (basically a one hour training session during lunch time) offered by Compute Canada dealing with Slurm, GNU Parallel and how to combine them. This was a very useful and timely presentation for me (&amp;#x1f1eb;&amp;#x1f1f7; slides available online &amp;#x1f517;) as I&amp;rsquo;ve just got started with Slurm (see my previous notes on the topic) and was eager to learn more.
Earlier today, I found an opportunity to put in practice what I&amp;rsquo;ve learned last week.</description></item><item><title>Retrieve a list of publications available from an ORCID account with R</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2019/11/2019-11-10_retrieve_a_list/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2019/11/2019-11-10_retrieve_a_list/</guid><description>ORCID is a great initiative that provides a unique identifier for researchers (akin to a DOI but for people). In my opinion, the two main/direct benefits from having an ORCID account are:
a web page with details about researcher background and publication (see mine at https://orcid.org/0000-0001-6619-9874 and check out this previous note on the topic);
an ORCID account can be used to log in the web interfaces of various scientific journals so that research have a centralized login and personal details for various journals (see the log in page of Global Ecology and Biogeography as an example &amp;#x2b07;&amp;#xfe0f;).</description></item><item><title>Installing Node.js and npm on Debian Buster</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2019/11/2019-11-06_installing_node_js/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2019/11/2019-11-06_installing_node_js/</guid><description>Node.js was developed to run JavaScript everywhere (as opposed to solely in a web browser) which led to the development of a lot of software written in JavaScript (arguably the most popular programming language, see the survey by StackOverflow and the RedMonk&amp;rsquo;s one). I personally use several pieces of it, for instance gtop and decktape and I install them with the dedicated package manager, namely npm.
A few days ago, I had a hard time installing decktape &amp;mdash; that I use to convert my HTML presentations to pdf files &amp;mdash; on my Debian Buster computer, and so I decided to do a fresh install of Node.</description></item><item><title>Convert a pdf file to a text file with pdftotext</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2019/11/2019-11-04_convert_a_pdf/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2019/11/2019-11-04_convert_a_pdf/</guid><description>Today I was asked whether I was aware of a way to extract a table from a pdf file. I actually knew about one CLI tool pdftotext &amp;#x1f517; that converts a pdf file to a text file and I had this memory that I had used it for tables in the past. pdftotext is developed by Glyph &amp;amp; Cog with several other CLI tools to manipulate pdf files and the pdf viewer Xpdf.</description></item><item><title>Prezto's aliases for git</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2019/11/2019-11-01_prezto_s_aliases/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2019/11/2019-11-01_prezto_s_aliases/</guid><description>A few days ago, as I was having a look at the list of aliases I use with Zsh, I realized that there was a ton of aliases available that I did not created:
1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 $ alias g=git gCO=&amp;#39;gCo $(gCl)&amp;#39; gCT=&amp;#39;gCt $(gCl)&amp;#39; gCa=&amp;#39;git add $(gCl)&amp;#39; gCe=&amp;#39;git mergetool $(gCl)&amp;#39; gCl=&amp;#39;git --no-pager diff --name-only --diff-filter=U&amp;#39; gCo=&amp;#39;git checkout --ours --&amp;#39; gCt=&amp;#39;git checkout --theirs --&amp;#39; [.</description></item><item><title>Combine multiple pdf files</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2019/10/2019-10-24_combine_multiple_pdf/</link><pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2019/10/2019-10-24_combine_multiple_pdf/</guid><description>For a recent job application, I needed to combine several pdf files into a single one and to number its pages afterwards. I already knew that I would be able to use PDFtk, a smart CLI tool I mentioned in a previous note to combine the pdf files, but I was not sure how to proceed for the page numbering. Turns out that PDFtk is also useful for this too!</description></item><item><title>Deploy a pkgdown on gh-pages</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2019/10/2019-10-22_deploy_a_pkgdown/</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2019/10/2019-10-22_deploy_a_pkgdown/</guid><description>There are three ways to deploy a website on your GitHub pages :
using the gh-pages; using the folder docs on your master branch; using the master branch. I frequently use the GitHub pages to deploy the pkgdown websites I create for my R packages. For a while, I was using the docs/ folder where the website is generated by default. But I figured that this way has two main drawbacks:</description></item><item><title>rmangal `[REDIRECT]`</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2019/10/2019-10-22_rmangal_redirect/</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2019/10/2019-10-22_rmangal_redirect/</guid><description>A very short note to mention that yesterday Steve Vissault and I published a post on rOpenSci about rmangal &amp;#x1f517;. In a nutshell rmangal is an R client for the Mangal database that includes &amp;gt; 1300 ecological networks. Check out the cool poster Steve created.</description></item><item><title>Compendium hebdomadaire #001</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/perso/opinions/compendium001/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/perso/opinions/compendium001/</guid><description>Durant la semaine du 30 Septembre, trois thèmes ont attiré mon attention:
un questionnement sur la démocratie participative la transparence en temps de crise le schisme de réalité sur les enjeux climatiques Besoin de démocratie participative? Cela fait quelques mois que je me questionne sur la démocratie participative et plus précisément sur son articulation avec la démocratie représentative. Cette semaine, dans la presse française, les 150 citoyens tirés aléatoirement pour réfléchir aux enjeux climatiques ont donné une bonne occasion d&amp;rsquo;en parler.</description></item><item><title>Ecrire ses opinions prend du temps!</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/perso/opinions/ecriresesopinions/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/perso/opinions/ecriresesopinions/</guid><description>Il y a quelques temps, j&amp;rsquo;ai ouvert cette section dans le but de structurer un peu mes idées et approfondir certains sujets. C&amp;rsquo;est, à mon sens, un travail très valorisant bien que chronophage. Actuellement, j&amp;rsquo;ai plusieurs ébauches de textes que je trouve intéressantes mais qui demandent encore du travail! Initialement, je pensais partager un texte par semaine mais avec mes autres activités, cela me semble peu réaliste. Pour cette raison, j&amp;rsquo;ai réfléchi à une nouvelle formule pour cette section: chaque semaine je rassemble quelques opinions autour de l’actualité dans une forme de compendium et de temps à une autre (une fois par mois étant mon objectif) je partage un texte avec un peu plus de profondeur.</description></item><item><title>The fontawesome5 Latex package</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2019/10/2019-10-01_the_fontawesome5_latex/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2019/10/2019-10-01_the_fontawesome5_latex/</guid><description>Font Awesome is a very popular icon set used on websites to improve the visual grepping. For instance, whenever I point to a GitHub repository on my website I use &amp;lt;i class=&amp;quot;fa fa-github&amp;quot; aria-hidden=&amp;quot;true&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/i&amp;gt; to add the following icon that indicates, to people familiar with GitHub, the kind of content the link points to.
Visual grepping is somewhat powerful and months ago I started to use this icon set in my CV (see KevCaz/CV_latex) via the fontawesome Latex package that was maintained by Xavier Danaux (see xdanaux/fontawesome-latex).</description></item><item><title>Homogenization of freshwater lakes</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/econotes/2019/homogenontario/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/econotes/2019/homogenontario/</guid><description>This was originally posted on https://mccannlab.ca/post/2019/09/20/homogenization-of-freshwater-lakes/
English version &amp;#x1f1ec;&amp;#x1f1e7; What happened to fish communities in Ontario lakes over the last few decades? We have been relentlessly looking for answers to this question! Indeed, we did our best to determine whether global change has affected those communities over the last 40 years. It turns out that fish communities in Ontario lakes are pretty different from what they were, but climate change does not explain those changes &amp;#x1f4a5;!</description></item><item><title>From Mammoth to Graham</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2019/09/2019-09-19_from_mammoth_to/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2019/09/2019-09-19_from_mammoth_to/</guid><description>Compute Canada is awesome! Seriously, it is! As explained on its website:
Compute Canada, in partnership with regional organizations ACENET, Calcul Québec, Compute Ontario and WestGrid, leads the acceleration of research and innovation by deploying state-of-the-art advanced research computing (ARC) systems, storage and software solutions. Together we provide essential ARC services and infrastructure for Canadian researchers and their collaborators in all academic and industrial sectors. Our world-class team of more than 200 experts employed by 37 partner universities and research institutions across the country provide direct support to research teams.</description></item><item><title>R-3.6.1 on Ubuntu Bionic</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2019/09/2019-09-11_r_3_6/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2019/09/2019-09-11_r_3_6/</guid><description>As detailed in this post, I recently installed Ubuntu on my old MacBookPro (assuming a MacBookPro from mid-2012 is old &amp;#x1f60f;). In order to run some simulations I needed to install the latest version of R. I first followed the procedure to install the latest R on Debian before realizing that the backport for Ubuntu are different &amp;#x1f601;! So if you are on Ubuntu, the correct link to install the latest R is here.</description></item><item><title>Memory issue with ImageMagick</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2019/08/2019-08-26_memory_issue_with/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2019/08/2019-08-26_memory_issue_with/</guid><description>Today, I was combining a set of images like so:
1 $ convert -append figP*.png out.png when I got error stating that cache resources exhausted. I was first surprised because it was the same set of images I combined a couple of days before EXCEPT that I significantly increased their resolution. So I googled the error message and found this issue on the GitHub repository of ImageMagick.
Well, turns out it was not a issue at all, I simply needed to change the memory limit as explained here and well summarized in the issue:</description></item><item><title>A simple yet powerful unit converter with R</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2019/08/2019-08-06_a_simple_yet/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2019/08/2019-08-06_a_simple_yet/</guid><description>I always forget how to convert Fahrenheit to Celsius and conversely, which I find very frustrating &amp;ndash; for the record the current definition is:
$$T(°F) = T(°C)\frac{9}{5}+32$$
Yesterday, after looking for the umpteenth times the above equation I decided to create a small function that would handle the conversion. I first thought that I could create a 2-lines function just for this specific unit conversion when I realize that there is a R &amp;#x1f4e6; dedicated to units manipulation: units that depends on the C library libdunits2 and is required to install &amp;#x1f4e6; sf.</description></item><item><title>Variables in mathematical expressions in a plot with R</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2019/08/2019-08-02_variables_in_mathematical/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2019/08/2019-08-02_variables_in_mathematical/</guid><description>It is rather straightforward to add mathematical annotation in a plot with R. However, I have noted that people struggle with the two following :
combining mathematical expression and text; using variables&amp;rsquo; values within an expression. The first one is actually easy, you just need to add and quotation marks to add text in expression and to use * to concatenate elements.
1 2 plot(c(0,1), c(0,1), type = &amp;#34;n&amp;#34;) text(0.5, .</description></item><item><title>GitHub pages site with Jekyll locally</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2019/07/2019-07-27_github_pages_site/</link><pubDate>Sat, 27 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2019/07/2019-07-27_github_pages_site/</guid><description>I use GitHub pages (aka gh-pages) very often now and find this feature extremely powerful for various reasons. This web site for instance, is first checked on Travis CI and then deployed to GitHub pages, which is way more convenient than using FileZilla.
Recently, I have been working on a small site for the QCBS that needed a site to introduce their R workshops. We (I was not the only one on board) decided to use the GitHub pages with Jekyll and one of the existing them, minima, that is we opt for using gh-pages the easiest way.</description></item><item><title>Use Gogh to color your terminal!</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2019/07/2019-07-26_use_gogh_to/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2019/07/2019-07-26_use_gogh_to/</guid><description>As mentioned in a previous note, I now use Atom together with Gnome Terminal for most of my coding and writing time and really enjoy my current setup. As I use two different applications, I have similar but slightly different color schemes, which, weirdly enough, has been bugging me for a while&amp;hellip; That is why, a few days ago, I started to edit the color but looking a the them repository of the Atom theme I liked (e.</description></item><item><title>SageMath version 8.6 on Debian Buster</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2019/07/2019-07-18_sagemath_version_8/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2019/07/2019-07-18_sagemath_version_8/</guid><description>This is a short note to follow up on a previous one where I reported the steps to install the latest release of Sage using the GitHub repository. At that time Sage version 8.3 was not available on Debian Buster but now version 8.6 is available on Buster! Given the set of dependencies of Sage, I guessed it was quite a challenge to pack it up, so &amp;#x1f44f; to the relentless Debian package maintainers because thanks to them all I need to install Sage is:</description></item><item><title>Dual Boot MacOS-Ubuntu</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2019/07/2019-07-16_dual_boot_macos/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2019/07/2019-07-16_dual_boot_macos/</guid><description>Context I must say that I have been quite unhappy with my old Mac Book Pro (mid 2012) for almost a year now. IIRC, I got it early 2013 and it served me well during my PhD but now it is kind of slow &amp;#x1f422; and often behaves weirdly on boot. Last weekend fir instance, I got a nasty black screen on boot &amp;#x1f631;. Turns out it happens frequently and there are no less than four different solutions to this issue &amp;#x1f631; (in my case, emptying the PRAM did the job)&amp;hellip; Windows, MacOS, blue screen, black screen, yunno&amp;hellip; I found having these issues actually rather worrisome because I care about my computer, I update it frequently and I&amp;rsquo;m actually capable of solving this kind of issues, so WTF?</description></item><item><title>My Raspberry Pi 3B</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2019/07/2019-07-12_my_raspberry_pi/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2019/07/2019-07-12_my_raspberry_pi/</guid><description>Two years ago now, I bought myself a Raspberry Pi 3B (back in 2015, I bought a model 2B and since June of this year, model 4B is out but has some issues). Even if don&amp;rsquo;t use it as much as I would like to, this small computer never ceases to amaze me! The concept is awesome, the education goals are meaningful and timely and the community is great, just check out the official website https://www.</description></item><item><title>More digits!</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2019/07/2019-07-11_more_digits/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2019/07/2019-07-11_more_digits/</guid><description>SageMath has tons of powerful features (I explain how to install the latest version on Debian buster in a previous note), one relatively simple and very handy function I&amp;rsquo;ve recently used is numerical_approx() (see the documentation) that returns (suspense = 0) a numerical approximation for any number of digits!
In my case, I was looking for a 40 digits approximation of 4*pi/(6+sqrt(38)). Using a programming language such as R, I would have had to tweak the printing format:</description></item><item><title>Debian 10 *buster* released</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2019/07/2019-07-09_debian_10_buster/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2019/07/2019-07-09_debian_10_buster/</guid><description>I have been on Debian buster for more than a year while it was the Debian Testing. After a frozen period that lasted a few months, buster is the new stable Debian distribution since yesterday!
What does this change on my end? Not much! Basically, as I was already using buster in my /etc/apt/sources.list.d/ file, when I used apt-get update I got the following message:
1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 Get:1 http://security.</description></item><item><title>Reasonably complex matrix build with Travis</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2019/07/2019-07-02_reasonably_complex_matrix/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2019/07/2019-07-02_reasonably_complex_matrix/</guid><description>Matrix build is a very powerful feature of Travis CI: it allows you to define a list of custom environments wherein your software will be built. For instead, I check rcites on 4 different environments (note that Travis offers 3 different Ubuntu version, several MacOSX images and that the support for Windows is in early stage).
A few days ago, the matrix build I used for another R &amp;#x1f4e6; failed with the following error (see https://travis-ci.</description></item><item><title>Upgrading to R.3.6.0 on Debian Buster</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2019/06/2019-06-26_upgrading_to_r/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2019/06/2019-06-26_upgrading_to_r/</guid><description>Since March of this year, Debian Buster (Debian 10) has been frozen and has become the new stable release and for this reason the installation of R 3.6.0 (available since April 26th) on Buster requires the backports kindly provided by Johannes Ranke. Yesterday, I decided to install R 3.6.0 on my computer, so I used them, which basically means that:
I appended deb http://cran.wu.ac.at/bin/linux/debian buster-cran35/ to /etc/apt/sources.list; I added the key to configure the secure apt.</description></item><item><title>Des opinions, moi?</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/perso/opinions/desopinions/</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/perso/opinions/desopinions/</guid><description>Je me suis récemment fait demander si j&amp;rsquo;avais des opinions. La question était posée ainsi, sans référence à un sujet particulier. Une bien drôle de question&amp;hellip; peut-on seulement ne pas avoir d&amp;rsquo;opinion?
Le dictionnaire de l&amp;rsquo;Académie Français propose, pour l&amp;rsquo;entrée opinion, trois acceptions que je reporte ici:
1- Avis donné sur une question discutée dans une assemblée, au sein d&amp;rsquo;une compagnie;
2- Sentiment, idée, point de vue ; jugement que l&amp;rsquo;on porte, sans que l&amp;rsquo;esprit le tienne pour assuré, sur une question donnée;</description></item><item><title>inSilecoMisc v0.2.0</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2019/06/2019-06-21_insilecomisc_v0_2/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2019/06/2019-06-21_insilecomisc_v0_2/</guid><description>For 3 years now, I have been maintaining a small R &amp;#x1f4e6; named inSilecoMisc that includes a set of of handy functions. As time goes, my skills evolves (hopefully in a good direction) and so does the content of these packages: I had function that suit my new needs, I realize that some functions I wrote are (better) coded elsewhere, I rewrite functions to make then more intuitive and I improve the documentation.</description></item><item><title>Send a set of command lines to GNOME Terminal</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2019/06/2019-06-10_send_a_set/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2019/06/2019-06-10_send_a_set/</guid><description>Context As mentioned several times on this website, I use Atom for my coding as well as for writing posts and manuscripts. While coding, one often needs to run commands in a terminal. To do so, I use specific Atom packages such as IDE-R or Julia Client to run R and Julia commands respectively and platformio-ide-terminal. The latter meets most of my expectations, but:
the terminal emulated is in a bottom panel and when I&amp;rsquo;m working on my laptop I cannot get a good overview of the code and the corresponding outputs at the same time, pretty annoying&amp;hellip; and having the terminal in the right panel is a feature unlikely to be implemented in a near future;</description></item><item><title>Extract a range of pages from a pdf file</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2019/05/2019-05-30_extract_a_range/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2019/05/2019-05-30_extract_a_range/</guid><description>Today, I was looking for a way to extract pages from a pdf file with the command line interface and stumbled on this answer on , and so I decided to try PDFtk. After a quick installation (apt-get install pdftk), I simply reproduced the example in the answer with my file!
1 $ pdftk book.pdf cat 34-45 output chapter2.pdf Very handy, quite easy to use and efficient! Digging a little more the documentation, it turns out that you can do way more!</description></item><item><title>Sent your R package to package builder via devtools</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2019/05/2019-05-23_sent_your_r/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2019/05/2019-05-23_sent_your_r/</guid><description>As I was sending a minor patch to rcites, I use devtools::build_win() and got the following warning message:
Warning message: &amp;#39;devtools::build_win&amp;#39; is deprecated. And the message suggested to check out check_win_*, and I so did a quick check:
1 R&amp;gt; devtools::check once tab typed, the following function names were prompted:
1 2 3 4 devtools::check_built devtools::check_cran devtools::check_win_oldrelease devtools::check_man devtools::check devtools::check_win_release devtools::check_win_devel devtools::check_dep_version devtools::check_failures devtools::check_rhub We now have access to rhub via devtools, that&amp;rsquo;s neat &amp;#x1f386;!</description></item><item><title>Emoticons in commit messages for manuscripts</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2019/05/2019-05-20_emoticons_in_commit/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2019/05/2019-05-20_emoticons_in_commit/</guid><description>I recently wrote a note about using emoticons in a standard way in commit messages and I now use them in a standard way following Gitmoji. I do so for my code, but I also use git for manuscrits and I also try to standardize the way I use emoticons in that case. Below is the set of emoticons I am currently using for manuscrits:
&amp;#x1f4dd; pencil add a significant piece of writing, paragraph; &amp;#x270f;&amp;#xfe0f; pencil2typos; &amp;#x1f4ca; bar_chart figures added or edited (figure or its caption); &amp;#x1f5d1;&amp;#xfe0f; wastebasket delete an file; &amp;#x2728; sparkles integrate co-author&amp;rsquo;s comment(s)/work; &amp;#x1f389; tada address reviewer&amp;rsquo;s comment(s); &amp;#x2b06;&amp;#xfe0f; arrow_up version submitted; &amp;#x1f680; rocket version accepted.</description></item><item><title>Combine images with ImageMagick</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2019/05/2019-05-16_combine_images_with/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2019/05/2019-05-16_combine_images_with/</guid><description>I do love create figures with R, I found quite satisfying to make them very personalized, yet reproducible! However I sometime wish that combining two plots was easier (as it often requires to build larges matrices and crazy layout() calls). I was looking for a simple way to do basic combinations of customized R figures, and I stumbled on this discussion on showing how easy it is to do so with ImageMagick.</description></item><item><title>Multiple-protocol with aria2</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2019/05/2019-05-10_multiple_protocol_with/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2019/05/2019-05-10_multiple_protocol_with/</guid><description>People at TecMint write great posts and gather tons of tips about Linux. Recently, they twitted about aria2:
Aria2 – A Multi-Protocol Command-Line #Download Tool for #Linux https://t.co/u7GM9Sgozu via @tecmint RT @linuxtoday pic.twitter.com/1GMGKHOEYA
&amp;mdash; Linux Inside: The Ideal Blog for Sysadmins &amp;amp; Geeks (@tecmint) April 29, 2019 I gave it a try, and it&amp;rsquo;s pretty sweet &amp;#x1f604;! With a simple command line, you can download any file using any of the most common transfer protocols!</description></item><item><title>Merging .bib files with bibtool</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2019/04/2019-04-22_merging_bib_files/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2019/04/2019-04-22_merging_bib_files/</guid><description>As researchers, we sometimes write manuscripts collectively and remotely in LaTeX (or in a lightweight markup languages that is converted into LaTeX at some point). In such case, it is quite useful to let co-authors edit their own bib file in order to store the references included in the part of the manuscript they are editing. One way to deal with several bib files is to merge them into one bib file before compiling the final document to pdf.</description></item><item><title>Cannot boot again `[SOLVED]`</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2019/03/2019-03-18_cannot_boot_again/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2019/03/2019-03-18_cannot_boot_again/</guid><description>Within the last two weeks, I ran into serious issues with my Debian machine. Two weeks ago, just as I described in a previous post, after some updates, I was not able to boot anymore. Given that everything was working very well before, I was convinced that this was an issue with GRUB2, but was not able to fix it despite a very demanding quest for a solution. I was so desperate that I decided to reinstall Debian (which turned out to be a good thing as it fixed minor issues I had with my hardware.</description></item><item><title>Even more internet radio stations</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2019/03/2019-03-15_even_more_internet/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2019/03/2019-03-15_even_more_internet/</guid><description>As mentioned in a previous post, I love listening to internet radios and a few months ago I discovered Audiophile radios which I&amp;rsquo;ve enjoyed very much for four months. But it looks like Audiophile is down now &amp;#x1f622; (hopefully just temporarily). So, today I spent some time looking for more internet radio stations that offer high quality streams and I found those valuable links:
listenlive.eu that lists radios for European countries, e.</description></item><item><title>Emoticons in commit messages</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2019/02/2019-02-17_emoticons_in_commit/</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2019/02/2019-02-17_emoticons_in_commit/</guid><description>When you are working on a project with GitHub (or a similar web service based on ) that has tens of commits, using emoticons in commit messages makes the search in the history of your project very efficient. To add one emoticon to your commit message, you must use its name (check this cheat sheet) within colons in the commit message, e.g. &amp;ldquo;add this :emoticon_name:&amp;rdquo;. Personally, I mostly use the following emoticon:</description></item><item><title>rgeos v0.4-2</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2019/02/2019-02-02_rgeos_v0_4/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2019/02/2019-02-02_rgeos_v0_4/</guid><description>As explained in a previous note, a few weeks ago I was not able to install rgeos version 0.4-1. I ran into a new issue today and I decided to figure out what was wrong with it. After a quick search, I found this answer on and it turned out that all I needed was to install libgeos++-dev and so I did:
sudo apt install libgeos++-dev After that the command:</description></item><item><title>Merge .csv files into a single .xlsx file with ssconvert</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2019/01/2019-01-15_merge_csv_files/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2019/01/2019-01-15_merge_csv_files/</guid><description>In a previous note, I explained how to convert .xlsx into .csv with ssconvert. Today, I wanted to do the reverse operation, so I looked up on the Internet and found this answer on ubuntu forums: assuming you need to merge file1.csv and file2.csv into all.xlsx (in two separate sheets) then all you have to do is:
ssconvert --merge-to=all.xlsx file1.csv file2.csv The short option for --merge-to= is -M (see man ssconvert), so what I did was:</description></item><item><title>Julia v1.1-rc1 from source</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2019/01/2019-01-13_julia_v1_1/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2019/01/2019-01-13_julia_v1_1/</guid><description>Learning more about Julia is one of the many things I attempt to do in 2019 &amp;#x1f604;. Few weeks ago, I installed Julia 1.0.0 using the GitHub repository and I decided to checkout how easy it would be to upgrade to the version to v1.1.0-rc1 (note that &amp;ldquo;rc&amp;rdquo; stands for release candidate). It was quite easy, all I had to do was:
git checkout master git pull git checkout v1.1.0-rc1 make 1h13min42sec latter, julia 1.</description></item><item><title>Get docker on Debian Testing</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2019/01/2019-01-07_get_docker_on/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2019/01/2019-01-07_get_docker_on/</guid><description>One of my resolutions for 2019 is to use docker to delve deeper into reproducible science. As explained in the Wikipedia&amp;rsquo;s article about docker:
Docker is a computer program that performs operating-system-level virtualization, also known as &amp;ldquo;containerization&amp;rdquo;.
Basically, instead of installing software in a way that very much likely depends on the Operating System (OS) you are using, you install docker (OS specific) and then you run command lines (not OS specific) to install the set of containers (software) you need.</description></item><item><title>Get a list of your publications with ORCID</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2018/12/2018-12-29_get_a_list/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2018/12/2018-12-29_get_a_list/</guid><description>ORCID provides you with an unique research identifier that can be used as a login on journals&amp;rsquo; website, a identifier for your papers, R packages (see below), and more).
Your identifier is actually associated with a webpage (see mine: https://orcid.org/0000-0001-6619-9874) where you can edit your profile, get a QR code, etc.
It is very easy to search and &amp;ldquo;add works&amp;rdquo; to your account.
Moreover, if the journal you have published with allows you to add your ORCID, your profile will be automatically updated.</description></item><item><title>How to partition your external hard drive</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2018/12/2018-12-22_how_to_partition/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2018/12/2018-12-22_how_to_partition/</guid><description>Recently, I formatted an external hard drive and I created several partitions on it. For doing so, I used to very good tools:
Disks (gnome-disks); GParted (GNOME Partition Editor). Both tools are intuitive and makes your live really easy. You can also find good tutorials on line (e.g. looks at this answer on for a step by step GParted tutorial). I&amp;rsquo;ve just realized that GParted is actually the GUI for GNU Parted that will try next time I want to partition an hard drive (I&amp;rsquo;ve spotted this tuto &amp;#x1f604;).</description></item><item><title>Cannot boot after upgrade on Debian Testing `[SOLVED]`</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2018/12/2018-12-17_cannot_boot_after/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2018/12/2018-12-17_cannot_boot_after/</guid><description>Yesterday, I upgraded some packages on my Debian machine as I regularly do (cannot remember the exact list) but when I rebooted the system, I was not able to access the file system anymore &amp;#x1f631;.
It was the first time I had no clue about what I did wrong and also the first time I had no idea of what to do. Basically, every time I started my computer, I ended up on a page I had never seen before where I had only two options:</description></item><item><title>My programming fonts!</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2018/11/2018-11-22_my_programming_fonts/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2018/11/2018-11-22_my_programming_fonts/</guid><description>Given that I spend most of my working time on a code editor (including to write papers), I regard the choice of the font as quite important. To me, a programming font must be monospaced (programming without a monospaced font is quite challenging) and appeal to me (a matter of readability and aesthetic I guess).
There are tons of fonts nowadays and it is quite easy to create your own (see for instance fontstruc), so the choice is wide!</description></item><item><title>How many `&amp;` or `|` ?</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2018/11/2018-11-21_how_many_or/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2018/11/2018-11-21_how_many_or/</guid><description>Recently, I reviewed a paper that introduces a package, so I reviewed the code and noticed that the authors often used &amp;amp;&amp;amp; (and) and || (or) whereas only &amp;amp; and | were required. I guess this is due to:
other programming language; the fact that for vectors of one element in R &amp;amp; and &amp;amp;&amp;amp; are equivalent (same for | and ||). Regarding point 1, we could take C as an example.</description></item><item><title>Find the Coordinate Reference System (CRS) you need</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2018/11/2018-11-20_find_the_coordinate/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2018/11/2018-11-20_find_the_coordinate/</guid><description>For the manipulation of spatial objects and spatial analyses, I mainly use R, meaning that I use R packages that turn R into a powerful Geographic Information System (GIS). Before 2017, I was using sp, rgdal, rgeos for vector objects and raster for raster objects. Now I use a combination of sf (created to replace sp, rgoes and rgdal), raster and sf and mapview.
One of the most common manipulation is to convert coordinates (see sf::st_transform() in raster::projectRaster()).</description></item><item><title>Run your jobs one by one on Travis!</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2018/11/2018-11-19_run_your_jobs/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2018/11/2018-11-19_run_your_jobs/</guid><description>I now test rcites for 4 configurations on Travis so Travis runs 4 jobs. For a while, I was running all the jobs at once, and as rcites is R-client for a web API, many of the jobs failed because of the well-known error 429:
Too Many Requests (RFC 6585) (HTTP 429).
I always ended restarting some jobs, I coped with it. At some point, I stepped back and thought: &amp;ldquo;people people behind Travis are smart, so they should have thought about limiting concurrent jobs&amp;rdquo;.</description></item><item><title>A bug in the command wrapper of r-core-base 3.5.1-1+b2</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2018/11/2018-11-18_a_bug_in/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2018/11/2018-11-18_a_bug_in/</guid><description>Today, as I working on a post, I got this issue when using the R command wrapper:
1 2 3 $ Rscript --no-site-file -e &amp;#39;blogdown::serve_site()&amp;#39; /usr/lib/R/bin/R: line 193: /usr/bin/sed: No such file or directory ERROR: option &amp;#39;-e&amp;#39; requires a non-empty argument I did not understand what happened so I decided to google it! The bug was already identified and reported &amp;#x1f604;. A side note to mention that several packages now imports callr (for instance pkgdown) and as it uses the R command wrapper (if I understand correctly) the current bug actually affects several different packages.</description></item><item><title>The number of dependencies</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2018/11/2018-11-16_the_number_of/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2018/11/2018-11-16_the_number_of/</guid><description>I was looking at some issues on GitHub when I found this example provided by Dirk Eddelbuettel to evaluate the number of species of a dependencies of a package. I decided to experiment a little bit package_dependencies().
1 2 3 4 R&amp;gt; library(tools) R&amp;gt; ap &amp;lt;- available.packages() R&amp;gt; nrow(ap) # nb available package [1] 13385 Retrieve the packages rcites depends on:
1 2 3 4 R&amp;gt; rc &amp;lt;- tools::package_dependencies(&amp;#34;rcites&amp;#34;, ap, &amp;#34;Imports&amp;#34;) R&amp;gt; rc $rcites [1] &amp;#34;httr&amp;#34; &amp;#34;jsonlite&amp;#34; &amp;#34;data.</description></item><item><title>Exceeding GitHub API rate limits?</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2018/11/2018-11-13_exceeding_github_api/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2018/11/2018-11-13_exceeding_github_api/</guid><description>Yesterday, while Travis was testing rcites I got this error message for the 3 jobs:
1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 Error: HTTP error 403. API rate limit exceeded for 104.154.255.220. (But here&amp;#39;s the good news: Authenticated requests get a higher rate limit. Check out the documentation for more details.) Rate limit remaining: 0/60 Rate limit reset at: 2018-11-12 23:24:16 UTC To increase your GitHub API rate limit - Use `usethis::browse_github_pat()` to create a Personal Access Token.</description></item><item><title>Clip, but crop first!</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2018/11/2018-11-10_clip_but_crop/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2018/11/2018-11-10_clip_but_crop/</guid><description>I often clip raster in R, with sf and raster it is straightforward and efficient. That said, I&amp;rsquo;d like to mention one tip tip R users that clip should be aware of: cropping before clipping. It does significantly improve the performance, as shown in the R script below:
1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 17 18 19 20 21 library(sf) library(raster) library(tidyverse) ## download Canada boundaries (level of the county) ont &amp;lt;- getData(&amp;#34;GADM&amp;#34;, country = &amp;#34;CAN&amp;#34;, level = 2) %&amp;gt;% st_as_sf %&amp;gt;% filter(NAME_1 == &amp;#34;Ontario&amp;#34;) ## Download elevation raster (NB resolution is coarse) can_elv &amp;lt;- getData(&amp;#34;alt&amp;#34;, country = &amp;#34;CAN&amp;#34;) R&amp;gt; system.</description></item><item><title>`sf` is fast</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2018/11/2018-11-09_sf_is_fast/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2018/11/2018-11-09_sf_is_fast/</guid><description>sf have become the new standard to read, manipulate, write vector files in R. I recently had a 1.6GB shapefiles that I needed to open
1 2 3 4 5 $ du geodata/* 717M geodata/OHN_WATERBODY.dbf 4.0K geodata/OHN_WATERBODY.prj 1.6G geodata/OHN_WATERBODY.shp 11M geodata/OHN_WATERBODY.shx and I was wondering about how much time it would take for sf to open it, and it was pretty fast &amp;#x1f680;
1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 R&amp;gt; system.</description></item><item><title>Thunderbird v60.3.0 solves them all!</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2018/11/2018-11-08_thunderbird_v60_3/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2018/11/2018-11-08_thunderbird_v60_3/</guid><description>As I mentioned in a previous note, when I installed the version 60.0-3 of Thunderbird I was no longer able to write new emails and so I had to downgrade to v.52.9.1. Since that time, things have gotten worst as I was no longer able to get hyperlinks opening the corresponding page in my web browser &amp;#x1f631;. I did not look for a fix, I simply coped with it waiting for an update.</description></item><item><title>Something wrong with rgeos 0.4-1?</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2018/11/2018-11-07_something_wrong_with/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2018/11/2018-11-07_something_wrong_with/</guid><description>The last update of rgeos (version 0.4-1) was released on October 19th, 2018 and with my current R set up:
1 2 3 4 R&amp;gt; sessionInfo() R version 3.5.1 (2018-07-02) Platform: x86_64-pc-linux-gnu (64-bit) Running under: Debian GNU/Linux buster/sid I got the following error:
1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 checking geos_c.h presence and usability... yes checking geos: linking with libgeos_c... no /usr/bin/ld: cannot find -lgeos collect2: error: ld returned 1 exit status configure: Install failure: compilation and/or linkage problems.</description></item><item><title>More radio stations</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2018/11/2018-11-04_more_radio_stations/</link><pubDate>Sun, 04 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2018/11/2018-11-04_more_radio_stations/</guid><description>I am a radio listener and a podcast addict &amp;#x1f4fb;! Yesterday, I spent some time adding more radio stations with Rhythmbox. I really love this software, it is simple and do everything I need, adding a new radio station with it was straightforward but it requires first to find the URLs of the radio stations to be added as there is no radio browser integrated (but have a look at radio-browser).</description></item><item><title>And the backlight buttons stopped responding!</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2018/10/2018-10-31_and_the_backlight/</link><pubDate>Wed, 31 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2018/10/2018-10-31_and_the_backlight/</guid><description>&amp;#x1f987; Happy Halloween! &amp;#x1f987; In order to celebrate, I thought it would be appropriate to write about something spooky &amp;#x1f47b;! So, as far as I remember, when I first installed Debian on my Lenovo T470p everything was OK, all the buttons were behaving just as expected, but, after a hibernation, the screen backlight buttons where not working anymore &amp;#x1f631;. Even more frightening, since that time, I am not able to change the intensity of the screen backlight from GNOME control center and since recently I have the same issue for the keyboard backlight &amp;#x1f631;.</description></item><item><title>Make your conditional statements efficient!</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2018/10/2018-10-30_make_your_conditional/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2018/10/2018-10-30_make_your_conditional/</guid><description>Recently, I was looking at an R function and found a if statement that looks something like this:
1 2 3 if (length(which(names(df) == &amp;#34;entry&amp;#34;)) &amp;gt; 0) { # [...] } I guess this is common way of doing it as it matches well with a way of looking at the problem: &amp;ldquo;if I want to test the presence of a column &amp;ldquo;entry&amp;rdquo; in a data frame (df), I can check if there is more at least one name that match &amp;ldquo;entry&amp;rdquo;.</description></item><item><title>Modify and combine a set of files in one</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2018/10/2018-10-29_modify_and_combine/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2018/10/2018-10-29_modify_and_combine/</guid><description>Today I was looking for a way to combine a set of files in one but before appending a given file, the 2 first lines as well as the last line had to be removed. On Stackoverflow I found a couple of answers (see questions 18006581, 12176492 and 5410757) and based on these I decided to use a combination of head and tail. I ended up creating the following shell script:</description></item><item><title>Make an image your favorite icon (favicon)</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2018/10/2018-10-24_make_an_image/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2018/10/2018-10-24_make_an_image/</guid><description>Favicon are every useful for visual grepping: we use them pretty much every day to quickly find a website in your bookmarks or to remember what a specific tab is about! Recently, I needed to convert a .png into a favicon, I knew that ImageMagick could handle this, here is the command line I used:
1 convert McTrickle.png -define icon:auto-resize=128,64,48,32,16 favicon.ico ImageMagick &amp;#x27a1;&amp;#xfe0f; &amp;#x1f44d; &amp;#x1f3c6;!</description></item><item><title>Make your computer talk!</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2018/10/2018-10-20_make_your_computer/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2018/10/2018-10-20_make_your_computer/</guid><description>When I was on MacOS, I really enjoyed the command say to make my macOS speak (another bad reason to procrastinate) and I was looking for a similar tool on Linux to make my Lenovo speak &amp;#x1f604;. After a quick search, I found two software: spd-say and espeak. They both offer the same basic options, similar to the ones say provides on MacOS.
spd-say spd-say was already included in the set of tools I install with Debian so I checked out the documentation with man spd-say:</description></item><item><title>.xlsx to .csv with ssconvert</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2018/10/2018-10-18_xlsx_to_csv/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2018/10/2018-10-18_xlsx_to_csv/</guid><description>Even if I use Calc more often than Gnumeric (and actually I tried to spend as less time as possible on spreadsheet programs), the latter provides a tool I&amp;rsquo;m fond of, ssconvert:
ssconvert - a command line spreadsheet format converter
It offers a very efficient way to convert .xlsx into .csv, for instance:
1 2 mkdir csvFiles ssconvert -S spreadsheet.xlsx csvFiles/%s.csv I the command lines above, I first create the folder &amp;lsquo;csvFiles&amp;rsquo; with mkdir and then I use ssconvert with option -S that stands for --export-file-per-sheet:</description></item><item><title>Mind your object and shared object files!</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2018/10/2018-10-17_mind_your_object/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2018/10/2018-10-17_mind_your_object/</guid><description>Rcpp profoundly changed the R landscape. Basically, it made all performance bottlenecks vanish and I&amp;rsquo;m not surprised that so many packages are now using it:
As of May 2017, 1026 packages on CRAN and a further 91 on BioConductor deploy Rcpp to extend R. (www.rcpp.org - October 17, 2018)
Even people that do not know nothing about Rcpp are likely to use it on a regular basis as most packages for data science are now linked to Rcpp (e.</description></item><item><title>From one character encoding to another</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2018/10/2018-10-16_from_one_character/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2018/10/2018-10-16_from_one_character/</guid><description>Today I needed to check the character encoding of a file, I found this page that explains how to do this. Basically the command file will give you the info, for instance:
1 2 $ file example.md example.md: ASCII text options -i for --mime and -b for --brief will give:
1 2 $ file -bi example.md text/plain; charset=us-ascii I figured out that I needed to convert my file from one character encoding to another and so I used iconv.</description></item><item><title>rcites code coverage dropped to 0</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2018/10/2018-10-09_rcites_code_coverage/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2018/10/2018-10-09_rcites_code_coverage/</guid><description>We (a couple of colleagues and myself) are currently finishing a major release for our R package rcites. After adding the latest feature I have been working on via a pull request, I messed up with my local master branch and overwrite/delete some files &amp;#x1f620;. I thought it was not a big deal as all of them were files created/edited when the package is built (well, I thought so). But after the very next push, the code coverage weirdly dropped to zero &amp;#x1f631;.</description></item><item><title>Resize image with Imagemagick</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2018/10/2018-10-05_resize_image_with/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2018/10/2018-10-05_resize_image_with/</guid><description>ImageMagick is a time saver! It&amp;rsquo;s designed and extremely powerful for manipulating images with a few command lines. Few weeks ago, I had to resize a bunch of .png images and realize how helpful ImageMagick could be is such case! All I had to do was creating a short shell script very similar to the following lines:
1 2 3 4 5 mkdir img_resized for f in *.png do convert $f -resize 250x250\&amp;gt; img_resized/${f%.</description></item><item><title>Let AppVeyor watch inSileco!</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2018/10/2018-10-02_let_appveyor_watch/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2018/10/2018-10-02_let_appveyor_watch/</guid><description>I very much enjoy sharing thoughts and code on our blog inSileco. Recently, one of the authors mentioned that he was not able to clone the repository on his Windows machine. I came to realize that we better not assume that everybody is working on MacOS or Linux and check that inSileco works well on Windows. One of the most convenient way to do so is to use AppVeyor and I therefore decided to spend some time making the build passed on AppVeyor!</description></item><item><title>Prompt before opening larges file in Atom</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2018/09/2018-09-29_prompt_before_opening/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2018/09/2018-09-29_prompt_before_opening/</guid><description>Many of the projects I am working on include files that are over 5Mo. When I am working with Atom I often click on them (wrongly) and this used to make Atom work hard for nothing &amp;#x1f61e;.
Your browser does not support the video tag. In the screencast above, for instance, I had to wait for 1 minute to be able to work again, although the file was 5 MB only (atom 1.</description></item><item><title>My Hugo shortcode for video</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2018/09/2018-09-27_my_hugo_shortcode/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2018/09/2018-09-27_my_hugo_shortcode/</guid><description>Shortcodes are among my favorite features in Hugo. As I am currently writing several notes a week that often include small screencasts, I thought that the time had come for me to create my own screencast shortcode. Here it is:
1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 &amp;lt;center&amp;gt; &amp;lt;video width=&amp;#39; {{ if .Get &amp;#34;width&amp;#34; }} {{ .Get &amp;#34;width&amp;#34; }} {{ else }} 100% {{ end }}&amp;#39; controls&amp;gt; &amp;lt;source src=&amp;#34;{{ .</description></item><item><title>One more scope in spell-check</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2018/09/2018-09-26_one_more_scope/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2018/09/2018-09-26_one_more_scope/</guid><description>I often use R markdown within Atom. By default, spell-check does not check .Rmd file and so I needed to add the corresponding scope to the list of grammars checked. It was a two steps process:
find the scope with the command: Log cursor scope (use the command-palette);
copy-paste the scope and add it to the list of scopes that are already checked.
Your browser does not support the video tag.</description></item><item><title>Unzip more than one file</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2018/09/2018-09-25_unzip_more_than/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2018/09/2018-09-25_unzip_more_than/</guid><description>Few days ago, I was trying to unzip a set of files and it did not work, so I looked up on the internet and found this very detailed post by Chris Jean that explains why
1 unzip path/*.zip gives you an error whereas
1 unzip &amp;#39;path/*.zip&amp;#39; works like a charm!
Thanks Chris!</description></item><item><title>Editing manuscripts in Atom</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2018/09/2018-09-24_editing_manuscripts_in/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2018/09/2018-09-24_editing_manuscripts_in/</guid><description>I use Atom not only for coding but also for manuscripts editing. It actually makes a ton of sense to me as I write my manuscripts in Markdown and Atom is provided with many powerful features (specific packages, shortcuts, etc.) that once combined make my writing very efficient (I like to think so). Recently, Timothée Poisot shared a very cool setup for academic writing with Atom.
As he does, I also enjoy autocomplete-bibtex and document-outline but I often get quite distracted by the preview and prefer working with a very minimalist environment, which is why I like the zen package so much!</description></item><item><title>How to count non-blank lines of a set of files?</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2018/09/2018-09-23_how_to_count/</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2018/09/2018-09-23_how_to_count/</guid><description>Yesterday, I was trying to find a way to count lines of a set of R files without comments nor empty lines and found this answer on stackoverflow:
1 cat R/* | sed &amp;#39;/^\s*#/d;/^\s*$/d&amp;#39; | wc -l Exactly what I needed! A few explanations are in order:
cat reads files sequentially; &amp;quot;|&amp;quot; is the the pipe operator; sed parses and transforms text; wc counts words, lines and more! Basically, counting lines of a file is done with the option -l of wc (option -m for characters, see man wc to learn more):</description></item><item><title>I love the 'multi-cursor-increment' package</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2018/09/2018-09-19_i_love_the/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2018/09/2018-09-19_i_love_the/</guid><description>I truly like the multiple cursors in Atom. I remember the first I used such feature, it was on Sublime Text, it blew my mind. I now use it pretty much everyday, and I have noticed that this is now a common feature among editors/IDEs, for instance, R users can use it in RStudio. Many time I hoped that a version of the multiple cursor would exist where it would be possible to set a sequence of number, I even thought that I should do it.</description></item><item><title>Back to Thunderbird 52.9.1!</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2018/09/2018-09-18_back_to_thunderbird/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2018/09/2018-09-18_back_to_thunderbird/</guid><description>Recently, Firefox 60 and Thunderbird 60 were made available for Debian Testing and I installed them. While I was and still am happy with Firefox 60, when I tried Thunderbird I had some issues&amp;hellip; Basically, I was not able to send a message and one of my favorite add-on, Markdown-Here, was not available for this version &amp;#x1f622;. So, I needed to get the previous version back. I searched for an answer and found this one, very helpful!</description></item><item><title>Use regex mode to efficiently find and replace in a specific folder with Atom</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2018/09/2018-09-17_use_regex_mode/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2018/09/2018-09-17_use_regex_mode/</guid><description>One specific feature of Atom I like is the &amp;ldquo;find and replace&amp;rdquo; for a specific folder (ctrl+shift+F by default on Debian). It could be extremely powerful when the regex mode is on. Let me give you an example. Yesterday I had to replace all \code{sometext} with 'sometext' which represented dozens of matches in several files. Well, it was not hard at all! All I had to do once the regex mode was on (see where the pointer is on the image below) was to remember the right regex:</description></item><item><title>My Lenovo T470p</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2018/09/2018-09-14_my_lenovo_t470p/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2018/09/2018-09-14_my_lenovo_t470p/</guid><description>When I switched from MacOS to Debian, I had no idea what laptop to buy so I searched for some information on the Internet. As expected it was hard to find reliable sources of information among websites that are obviously not neutral. After a few hours on the net, I ended up buying a Lenovo ThinkPad T470p and installed Debian on, so far so good, very happy I made this choice.</description></item><item><title>Use FFmpeg!</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2018/09/2018-09-13_use_ffmpeg/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2018/09/2018-09-13_use_ffmpeg/</guid><description>As mentioned on its website, FFmpeg is:
A complete, cross-platform solution to record, convert and stream audio and video.
FFmep is a powerful freeware, as mentioned on the Wikipedia page
FFmpeg includes libavcodec, an audio/video codec library used by many commercial and free software products, libavformat (Lavf),[6] an audio/video container mux and demux library, and the core ffmpeg command line program for transcoding multimedia files.
libavcodec is actually used in VLC a popular multimedia you may be familiar with.</description></item><item><title>Kernel 4.18</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2018/09/2018-09-12_kernel_4_18/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2018/09/2018-09-12_kernel_4_18/</guid><description>On Debian Testing today was a kernel update day! At 9:51am (Guelph time) I was still on kernel 4.17 &amp;#x1f631;
but at 9:53am, I was working with 4.18 &amp;#x1f3c6;
By the way, the source code of the kernel is mirrored on Github, a repository without an issue section with a $\infty$ number of contributors &amp;#x1f602;. Also, there is an exhaustive documentation available at https://www.kernel.org/doc/html/latest/.</description></item><item><title>More than one langage with spell-check</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2018/09/2018-09-11_more_than_one/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2018/09/2018-09-11_more_than_one/</guid><description>I spend most on my coding and writing time on Atom and as I write in both English and French I use two dictionaries with spell-check. Well, it actually took me a while to understand how to use two different locales on my Debian machine simply because I was lazy enough to not read the README on the Github repository of spell-check. Out of curiosity, I checked out what hunspell is (note that the project is hosted on Github) and then I checked the dictionaries currently installed on my device:</description></item><item><title>Building Sage 8.3 from sources on Debian Testing</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2018/09/2018-09-10_building_sage_8/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2018/09/2018-09-10_building_sage_8/</guid><description>Sage is a powerful mathematics software I use to do symbolic computation. Currently, there is no version available for Debian Testing, meaning you can either install the version available for the stable release or cherry pick the package available for Sid. Well I was not able to sudo apt-get the package for Stretch so I decided to use the same approach as I did for Julia (see this previous note). Basically, the sources of sage are mirrored on Github so one can clone the repository:</description></item><item><title>A few more LaTeX symbols</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2018/09/2018-09-08_a_few_more/</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2018/09/2018-09-08_a_few_more/</guid><description>Yesterday I learned 3 more LaTeX symbols while I was reviewing a paper &amp;#x1f63a;:
an equivalence symbol: $\equiv$ $\equiv$, use \xi not $\ksi$ for $\xi$, $\widehat{}$ for estimators (in statistics), for instance: $\widehat{\xi}$. Also, it was a good opportunity to remind myself that when looking for a specific symbol, one can always google an approximate description of the it, or one can use Detexify an extremely helpful LaTeX handwritten symbol recognition system!</description></item><item><title>Building Julia 1.0.0 from sources on Debian Testing</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2018/09/2018-09-06_building_julia_1/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2018/09/2018-09-06_building_julia_1/</guid><description>You may have already heard about Julia. Well, I am not (yet) a regular user but Julia&amp;rsquo;s performances are impressive, the langage is well-thought and the community is growing super fast, I therefore pay careful attention to what&amp;rsquo;s happening on their side. Recently, version 1.0.0 was released, so I decided to replace my local version v0.4.7.9 I installed with apt-get (note that currently v0.7.0-2 is available for Sid).
There are two ways to install Julia for Debian without apt-get.</description></item><item><title>Towards an integrated theory of biogeography</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/econotes/2016/towards-an-integrated-theory-of-biogeography/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/econotes/2016/towards-an-integrated-theory-of-biogeography/</guid><description>Dominique Gravel, Nicolas Mouquet, David Mouillot and I have recently published a paper in Ecography entitled &amp;lsquo;On the integration of biotic interaction and environmental constraints at the biogeographical scale&amp;rsquo; where we develop some ideas about how ecological interactions and abiotic factors must be taken together into account to better predict species&amp;rsquo; distribution. As suggested during the editing process, we wrote a blog post for Ecography that summarizes our paper. I think blog posts are an useful way to promote one&amp;rsquo;s work and also a good compromise between reading the abstract and reading the entire paper.</description></item><item><title>The ITER project</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/perso/opinions/old_iter/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/perso/opinions/old_iter/</guid><description>I wrote the lines below few months ago. I wanted to share them on line but at that time my website was not fully operational. As I dug out the text yesterday I post it on line today after few corrections.
I would like to share my feelings about the ITER project. Nature have recently published something on this topic and I think they could have explained way better the drawbacks of the project.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/talks/talks/esa_2016/presesakc/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/talks/talks/esa_2016/presesakc/</guid><description>&lt;!DOCTYPE html> Do ecological interactions impact geographic distributions of species? name: title layout: true class: center, middle, style1 --- # Do ecological interactions impact geographic distributions of species? &lt;hr /> ## 2016 ESA Annual Meeting, Fort Lauderdale ### Wednesday, August 10 ![:scale 60%](./img/bg.png) ### Kévin Cazelles &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; [http://kevincazelles.fr](http://kevincazelles.fr) &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; [&lt;i class="fa fa-github fa-2x" aria-hidden="true">&lt;/i>](https://github.com/KevCaz) ### Nicolas Mouquet, David Mouillot &amp; Dominique Gravel --- name: style2 layout: true class: center, middle, style2 --- count: false # CONTEXT &lt;hr/> ### Biogeography and ecological interactions --- name: style1 layout: true class: style1 --- # Geographic distribution &lt;hr/>&lt;br/> .</description></item><item><title/><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/talks/talks/seminaire/seminaire/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/talks/talks/seminaire/seminaire/</guid><description>&lt;!DOCTYPE html> Comment les interactions écologiques affectent-elles la distribution des espèces? name: title layout: true class: center, middle, style1 --- # Comment les interactions écologiques affectent-elles la répartition géographique des espèces? &lt;hr /> ## Séminaire (BIO9020) .left[### Jeudi 21 avril 2016, Rimouski] ![:scale 60%](./img/bg.png) ##[- Kévin Cazelles -](http://kevincazelles.fr) --- name: style2 layout: true class: center, middle, style2 --- count: false # CONTEXTE &lt;hr/> ### Biogéographie et interactions écologiques --- name: style1 layout: true class: style1 --- # Répartition géographique des espèces &lt;hr/>&lt;br/> .</description></item><item><title>&lt;i class='fas fa-book-open'>&lt;/i> Books I read and liked</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/perso/books/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/perso/books/</guid><description>Since 2018, I share the books I read and liked in this section (when I don&amp;rsquo;t enjoy a book I usually just stop reading it). As this section is a personal one, most of its content is written in French.
Depuis 2018, je partage quelques notes sur des livres que j&amp;rsquo;ai lu et apprécié (lorsque je n’apprécie pas la lecture d&amp;rsquo;un livre donné j&amp;rsquo;arrête simplement de le lire). C&amp;rsquo;est possible que quelques notes si dessous soient en anglais.</description></item><item><title>&lt;i class='fas fa-code'>&lt;/i> Software</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/software/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/software/</guid><description>Here are listed the software I significantly contributed to develop. To see more, check out my GitHub account.</description></item><item><title>&lt;i class='fas fa-file-alt'>&lt;/i> Publications</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/publications/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/publications/</guid><description/></item><item><title>&lt;i class='fas fa-project-diagram'>&lt;/i> About my research</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/about_my_research/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/about_my_research/</guid><description>I am Kevin Cazelles, I am a scientist who uses algebra, analysis, probability, statistics, data science and computational science
to study
ecological networks and how global change affects them
in order to
conserve ecosystem functions and biodiversity that are essential to our good health and well being.
As a quantitative ecologist, I tackle research challenges in various areas of ecology. I mainly focused on theory in macro-ecology and network ecology (check out my PhD dissertation ) but I also worked on various topics such as epidemics, forest dynamics, homogenization of fish communities, analysis of media coverage, meta-ecosystems and food security.</description></item><item><title>&lt;i class='fas fa-theater-masks'>&lt;/i> Movies and Series I watched and liked</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/perso/movies/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/perso/movies/</guid><description> Since late 2018, I share the movies ans series I watched and liked in this section. Note that images are links to the movies/series webpage available on Rotten Tomatoes.
2023 2022 2021 2020 2019 2018</description></item></channel></rss>