<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Atom on KevCaz's Website</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/tags/atom/</link><description>Recent content in Atom on KevCaz's Website</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Content under CC0 1.0 Universal unless otherwise specified.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 10 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://kevcaz.github.io/tags/atom/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Send a set of command lines to GNOME Terminal</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2019/06/2019-06-10_send_a_set/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2019/06/2019-06-10_send_a_set/</guid><description>Context As mentioned several times on this website, I use Atom for my coding as well as for writing posts and manuscripts. While coding, one often needs to run commands in a terminal. To do so, I use specific Atom packages such as IDE-R or Julia Client to run R and Julia commands respectively and platformio-ide-terminal. The latter meets most of my expectations, but:
the terminal emulated is in a bottom panel and when I&amp;rsquo;m working on my laptop I cannot get a good overview of the code and the corresponding outputs at the same time, pretty annoying&amp;hellip; and having the terminal in the right panel is a feature unlikely to be implemented in a near future;</description></item><item><title>Prompt before opening larges file in Atom</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2018/09/2018-09-29_prompt_before_opening/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2018/09/2018-09-29_prompt_before_opening/</guid><description>Many of the projects I am working on include files that are over 5Mo. When I am working with Atom I often click on them (wrongly) and this used to make Atom work hard for nothing &amp;#x1f61e;.
Your browser does not support the video tag. In the screencast above, for instance, I had to wait for 1 minute to be able to work again, although the file was 5 MB only (atom 1.</description></item><item><title>One more scope in spell-check</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2018/09/2018-09-26_one_more_scope/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2018/09/2018-09-26_one_more_scope/</guid><description>I often use R markdown within Atom. By default, spell-check does not check .Rmd file and so I needed to add the corresponding scope to the list of grammars checked. It was a two steps process:
find the scope with the command: Log cursor scope (use the command-palette);
copy-paste the scope and add it to the list of scopes that are already checked.
Your browser does not support the video tag.</description></item><item><title>Editing manuscripts in Atom</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2018/09/2018-09-24_editing_manuscripts_in/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2018/09/2018-09-24_editing_manuscripts_in/</guid><description>I use Atom not only for coding but also for manuscripts editing. It actually makes a ton of sense to me as I write my manuscripts in Markdown and Atom is provided with many powerful features (specific packages, shortcuts, etc.) that once combined make my writing very efficient (I like to think so). Recently, Timothée Poisot shared a very cool setup for academic writing with Atom.
As he does, I also enjoy autocomplete-bibtex and document-outline but I often get quite distracted by the preview and prefer working with a very minimalist environment, which is why I like the zen package so much!</description></item><item><title>I love the 'multi-cursor-increment' package</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2018/09/2018-09-19_i_love_the/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2018/09/2018-09-19_i_love_the/</guid><description>I truly like the multiple cursors in Atom. I remember the first I used such feature, it was on Sublime Text, it blew my mind. I now use it pretty much everyday, and I have noticed that this is now a common feature among editors/IDEs, for instance, R users can use it in RStudio. Many time I hoped that a version of the multiple cursor would exist where it would be possible to set a sequence of number, I even thought that I should do it.</description></item><item><title>Use regex mode to efficiently find and replace in a specific folder with Atom</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2018/09/2018-09-17_use_regex_mode/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2018/09/2018-09-17_use_regex_mode/</guid><description>One specific feature of Atom I like is the &amp;ldquo;find and replace&amp;rdquo; for a specific folder (ctrl+shift+F by default on Debian). It could be extremely powerful when the regex mode is on. Let me give you an example. Yesterday I had to replace all \code{sometext} with 'sometext' which represented dozens of matches in several files. Well, it was not hard at all! All I had to do once the regex mode was on (see where the pointer is on the image below) was to remember the right regex:</description></item><item><title>More than one langage with spell-check</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2018/09/2018-09-11_more_than_one/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2018/09/2018-09-11_more_than_one/</guid><description>I spend most on my coding and writing time on Atom and as I write in both English and French I use two dictionaries with spell-check. Well, it actually took me a while to understand how to use two different locales on my Debian machine simply because I was lazy enough to not read the README on the Github repository of spell-check. Out of curiosity, I checked out what hunspell is (note that the project is hosted on Github) and then I checked the dictionaries currently installed on my device:</description></item></channel></rss>