<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Ubuntu on KevCaz's Website</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/tags/ubuntu/</link><description>Recent content in Ubuntu on KevCaz's Website</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Content under CC0 1.0 Universal unless otherwise specified.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://kevcaz.github.io/tags/ubuntu/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>From Mantic Minotaur to Noble Numbat</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2024/05/2024-05-30_noble_numbat/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2024/05/2024-05-30_noble_numbat/</guid><description>Screenshot of my current desktop wallpaper, Little numbat boy by @azskalt, see The Coronation of a New Mascot: Noble Numbat. After a freezing phase that started last March, Ubuntu 24.04 codenamed Noble Numbat was released last April. It comes with a great deal of new features, listed in the release release notes.
As a Mantic Minotaur user, the option to update to Noble Numbat was presented in May, in a window that popped up after a regular update.</description></item><item><title>From Lunar Lobster to Mantic Minotaur</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2023/11/2023-11-05_from_lunar_lobster/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2023/11/2023-11-05_from_lunar_lobster/</guid><description>I have recently decided to upgrade to the most recent Ubuntu release on my Dell Precision machine, in other words, I wanted to get closer to Ubuntu&amp;rsquo;s release cycle. Previously, I would reinstall the latest long time release (LTS) every time a new update pops up (see the documentation). About 3 months ago, I switched to Ubuntu 23.04 (Lunar Lobster) and yesterday I upgraded to the October&amp;rsquo;s release, Mantic Minotaur (23.</description></item><item><title>Lack of boot space</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2023/03/2023-03-23_lack_of_boot/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2023/03/2023-03-23_lack_of_boot/</guid><description>On my Ubuntu 20.04 device at work, I ran into the same issue several times. Basically, I was not able to install the latest kernel because I was running out of boot space. As it turned out, the previous kernel images were kept and as I had only 700 Mb of boot space (/boot partition), after stacking a few images (most of them were OEM kernels) I was not able to update the kernel.</description></item><item><title>R-3.6.1 on Ubuntu Bionic</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2019/09/2019-09-11_r_3_6/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2019/09/2019-09-11_r_3_6/</guid><description>As detailed in this post, I recently installed Ubuntu on my old MacBookPro (assuming a MacBookPro from mid-2012 is old &amp;#x1f60f;). In order to run some simulations I needed to install the latest version of R. I first followed the procedure to install the latest R on Debian before realizing that the backport for Ubuntu are different &amp;#x1f601;! So if you are on Ubuntu, the correct link to install the latest R is here.</description></item><item><title>Dual Boot MacOS-Ubuntu</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2019/07/2019-07-16_dual_boot_macos/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2019/07/2019-07-16_dual_boot_macos/</guid><description>Context I must say that I have been quite unhappy with my old Mac Book Pro (mid 2012) for almost a year now. IIRC, I got it early 2013 and it served me well during my PhD but now it is kind of slow &amp;#x1f422; and often behaves weirdly on boot. Last weekend fir instance, I got a nasty black screen on boot &amp;#x1f631;. Turns out it happens frequently and there are no less than four different solutions to this issue &amp;#x1f631; (in my case, emptying the PRAM did the job)&amp;hellip; Windows, MacOS, blue screen, black screen, yunno&amp;hellip; I found having these issues actually rather worrisome because I care about my computer, I update it frequently and I&amp;rsquo;m actually capable of solving this kind of issues, so WTF?</description></item></channel></rss>