<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Ubuntu on KevCaz's Website</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/tags/ubuntu/</link><description>Recent content in Ubuntu on KevCaz's Website</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Content under CC0 1.0 Universal unless otherwise specified.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://kevcaz.github.io/tags/ubuntu/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>From Mantic Minotaur to Noble Numbat</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2024/05/2024-05-30_noble_numbat/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2024/05/2024-05-30_noble_numbat/</guid><description>&lt;center>
 &lt;figure>
 &lt;img class="mg-bot" src="./assets/noble_numbat.png" width="50%" >
 
 &lt;figcaption>&lt;div class="highlight justify">&lt;i class="fas fa-info-circle" aria-hidden>&lt;/i> Screenshot of my current desktop wallpaper, &lt;em>Little numbat boy&lt;/em> by @azskalt, see &lt;a href="https://ubuntu.com/blog/the-coronation-of-a-new-mascot-noble-numbat">&lt;em>The Coronation of a New Mascot: Noble Numbat&lt;/em>&lt;/a>.&lt;/div>&lt;/figcaption>
 
 &lt;/figure>
&lt;/center>

&lt;p>After a &lt;a href="https://lists.ubuntu.com/archives/ubuntu-devel-announce/2024-March/001343.htm">freezing phase&lt;/a> that started last March, Ubuntu 24.04 codenamed &lt;strong>Noble Numbat&lt;/strong> was released last April. It comes with a great deal of new features, listed in the release &lt;a href="https://discourse.ubuntu.com/t/ubuntu-24-04-lts-noble-numbat-release-notes/39890">release notes&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As a Mantic Minotaur user, the option to update to Noble Numbat was presented in May, in a window that popped up after a regular update. At first it did not work, so I hit &lt;code>sudo do-release-upgrade&lt;/code> to better understand the problem. I quickly figured out that that the issue stems from a package that I set on hold. After unholding it, the updating process worked like a charm.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>From Lunar Lobster to Mantic Minotaur</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2023/11/2023-11-05_from_lunar_lobster/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2023/11/2023-11-05_from_lunar_lobster/</guid><description>&lt;p>I have recently decided to upgrade to the most recent Ubuntu release on my Dell Precision machine, in other words, I wanted to get closer to &lt;a href="https://ubuntu.com/about/release-cycle">Ubuntu&amp;rsquo;s release cycle&lt;/a>. Previously, I would reinstall the latest long time release (LTS) every time a new update pops up (see &lt;a href="https://ubuntu.com/server/docs/upgrade-introduction">the documentation&lt;/a>).
About 3 months ago, I switched to Ubuntu 23.04 (Lunar Lobster) and yesterday I upgraded to the October&amp;rsquo;s release, &lt;a href="https://ubuntu.com/blog/ubuntu-desktop-23-10-mantic-minotaur-deep-dive">Mantic Minotaur (23.10)&lt;/a>.
The two upgrades were seamless, I just had to change a setting in the update-manager (see &lt;a href="https://help.ubuntu.com/community/LunarUpgrades">this&lt;/a>) and confirm the upgrade when I got notified. Once the installation completed, I had to edit a couple of source files for which only the latest LTS is available (22.04, a.k.a Jammy Jellyfish).
Here is my current configuration in a nutshell:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Lack of boot space</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2023/03/2023-03-23_lack_of_boot/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2023/03/2023-03-23_lack_of_boot/</guid><description>&lt;p>On my Ubuntu 20.04 device at work, I ran into the same issue several times. Basically, I was not able to install the latest kernel because I was running out of boot space. As it turned out, the previous kernel images were kept and as I had only 700 Mb of boot space (&lt;code>/boot&lt;/code> partition), after stacking a few images (most of them were &lt;a href="https://wiki.ubuntu.com/Kernel/OEMKernel">OEM kernels&lt;/a>) I was not able to update the kernel. After reading several posts (e.g. &lt;a href="https://askubuntu.com/questions/1207958/error-24-write-error-cannot-write-compressed-block">here&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://digitaliandm.com/2022/08/12/ubuntu-22-04-1-and-also-how-i-solved-the-fg-boot-space-issue/">there&lt;/a>) I was able to identify and delete the old kernel images that were no longer needed, i.g:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>R-3.6.1 on Ubuntu Bionic</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2019/09/2019-09-11_r_3_6/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2019/09/2019-09-11_r_3_6/</guid><description>&lt;p>As detailed in &lt;a href="../../notes/hardware/macosubuntu/">this post&lt;/a>, I recently installed
Ubuntu on my old MacBookPro (assuming a MacBookPro from mid-2012 is old
&amp;#x1f60f;). In order to run some simulations I needed to install the latest
version of R. I first followed &lt;a href="../../notes/r/r3_6_0onbuster/">the procedure to install the latest R on
Debian&lt;/a> before realizing that the backport for Ubuntu
are different &amp;#x1f601;! So if you are on Ubuntu, the correct link to install the
latest R is &lt;a href="https://cran.r-project.org/bin/linux/ubuntu/README.html">here&lt;/a>.
The 3-steps-procedure is pretty straight forward:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Dual Boot MacOS-Ubuntu</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2019/07/2019-07-16_dual_boot_macos/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2019/07/2019-07-16_dual_boot_macos/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="context">Context&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>I must say that I have been quite unhappy with my old Mac Book Pro (mid 2012)
for almost a year now. IIRC, I got it early 2013 and it served me well during my
PhD but now it is kind of slow &amp;#x1f422; and often behaves weirdly on boot. Last
weekend fir instance, I got a nasty black screen on boot &amp;#x1f631;. Turns out it
happens frequently and there are no less than &lt;a href="http://osxdaily.com/2014/11/22/fix-macbook-pro-booting-black-screen/">four different solutions to this
issue
&amp;#x1f631;&lt;/a>
(in my case, emptying the PRAM did the job)&amp;hellip; Windows, MacOS, blue screen,
black screen, yunno&amp;hellip; I found having these issues actually rather worrisome
because I care about my computer, I update it frequently and I&amp;rsquo;m actually
capable of solving this kind of issues, so WTF? This whole situation makes me
wonder what people unable to deal with this kind of problem would do&amp;hellip; My guess
is they would go to an fancy Apple store to either get it fixed &amp;#x1f4b0; or
get a new shinny Mac &amp;#x1f4b0;&amp;#x1f4b0;&amp;#x1f4b0;! Anyway, as the time went on, I started to feel frustrated and as I was not a big fan of &lt;a href="https://www.apple.com/ca/fr/macos/mojave/">MacOS Mojave&lt;/a> (it brings nothing I need and I haven&amp;rsquo;t noted any improvement). Given this I decided:&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>