<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Linux on KevCaz's Website</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/tags/linux/</link><description>Recent content in Linux on KevCaz's Website</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Content under CC0 1.0 Universal unless otherwise specified.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://kevcaz.github.io/tags/linux/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Reading 'The Linux command line' - Part I</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2024/03/2024-03-04_reading_the_linux/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2024/03/2024-03-04_reading_the_linux/</guid><description>I have been using the command line for more than 10 years now, I started on MacOS1 and I increased my usage of the Terminal when I switched to Linux. I am now comfortable with the Linux command line but still looking for ways to improve my skills. Recently, I stumbled into no starch press that offers a great selection of books and found out that several are available at the library.</description></item><item><title>Debian Bookworm setup -- update</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2023/02/2023-02-03_debian_bookworm_setup/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2023/02/2023-02-03_debian_bookworm_setup/</guid><description>I recently lent someone my Lenovo T470p and when I got it back, I decided to install Debian back on it (I installed Ubuntu 22.04 to make it easier to use for a non-Linux user). I went through all the installation seamlessly, but I was not able to have the wifi working. I knew it was related to firmware-iwlwifi, but I was unable to install it. As it turned out, the package was not available for bookworm (found this but looking at https://packages.</description></item><item><title>Debian Bookworm setup</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2022/05/2022-05-22_debian_bookworm_setup/</link><pubDate>Sun, 22 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2022/05/2022-05-22_debian_bookworm_setup/</guid><description>I recently decided to re-install my computer and I took the opportunity to create a gist that includes light version of my Debian 11 set-up, i.e. all the tools I used the most. Once again during the install (I use a Debian weekly build installation image) did not keep things light as I let several pieces of software be installed during the setup (e.g. LibreOffice, Inkscape). So here goes the 4th version of my bash script to install Debian on my Lenovo T470p ⬇️.</description></item><item><title>From Bullseye to Bookworm</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2021/08/2021-08-29_from_bullseye_to/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2021/08/2021-08-29_from_bullseye_to/</guid><description>Two weeks ago, Bullseye became the new stable Debian release. As I prefer using Debian testing, today, I jumped on Debian 12 codenamed Bookworm. To do so, I simply updated my source list by replacing instances of bullseye by bookworm, and then I used the combo apt update/ apt upgrade.
1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 17 18 19 20 $ apt-get update [.</description></item><item><title>Use flatpak!</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2021/02/2021-02-10_use_flatpak/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2021/02/2021-02-10_use_flatpak/</guid><description>Two days ago, I was attempting to install GNOME Fractal but apt-get couldn&amp;rsquo;t find it&amp;hellip; Cause it&amp;rsquo;s a GNOME application I thought is was unexpected, so I checked the README file. It turned out that the developers actually suggest to install their app with either Snap or Flatpak. As I knew about the former and hadn&amp;rsquo;t heard about the later, I decided to install flatpak.
1 $ apt install flatpak I then used flatpak to install Fractal.</description></item><item><title>Installing Spell Right on VSCodium v1.49</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2020/09/2020-09-21_installing_spell_right/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2020/09/2020-09-21_installing_spell_right/</guid><description>VSCodium is an automatic &amp;ldquo;clean&amp;rdquo; build of Virtual Studio Code (VSCode), i.e. a build without the Microsoft touch. VSCode (thus VSCodium) is very powerful, has a tons of features and its development is very dynamic, so I am always keeping an eye on what&amp;rsquo;s new with VSCode even though I am still using Atom more frequently.
When I set up Bullseye on my ThinkPad I installed the latest version of VSCodium and when I looked up for my favorite extensions, I realized that many extensions were actually missing.</description></item><item><title>Migrating from Buster to Bullseye</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2020/09/2020-09-18_migrating_from_buster/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2020/09/2020-09-18_migrating_from_buster/</guid><description>In July 2019, Buster became the stable release of Debian and the Bullseye became de facto the new testing distribution. After spending almost 2 years on Buster, I decided last week that it was time to migrate to Bullseye.
Backing up I frequently backup my files (so far with a simple bash function that copies them to my external hard drive). Plus, I also have a repository, dotfiles, where I stored my configuration files (the ones I can share).</description></item><item><title>Dual Boot MacOS-Ubuntu</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2019/07/2019-07-16_dual_boot_macos/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2019/07/2019-07-16_dual_boot_macos/</guid><description>Context I must say that I have been quite unhappy with my old Mac Book Pro (mid 2012) for almost a year now. IIRC, I got it early 2013 and it served me well during my PhD but now it is kind of slow 🐢 and often behaves weirdly on boot. Last weekend fir instance, I got a nasty black screen on boot 😱. Turns out it happens frequently and there are no less than four different solutions to this issue 😱 (in my case, emptying the PRAM did the job)&amp;hellip; Windows, MacOS, blue screen, black screen, yunno&amp;hellip; I found having these issues actually rather worrisome because I care about my computer, I update it frequently and I&amp;rsquo;m actually capable of solving this kind of issues, so WTF?</description></item><item><title>My Raspberry Pi 3B</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2019/07/2019-07-12_my_raspberry_pi/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2019/07/2019-07-12_my_raspberry_pi/</guid><description>Two years ago now, I bought myself a Raspberry Pi 3B (back in 2015, I bought a model 2B and since June of this year, model 4B is out but has some issues). Even if don&amp;rsquo;t use it as much as I would like to, this small computer never ceases to amaze me! The concept is awesome, the education goals are meaningful and timely and the community is great, just check out the official website https://www.</description></item><item><title>Debian 10 *buster* released</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2019/07/2019-07-09_debian_10_buster/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2019/07/2019-07-09_debian_10_buster/</guid><description>I have been on Debian buster for more than a year while it was the Debian Testing. After a frozen period that lasted a few months, buster is the new stable Debian distribution since yesterday!
What does this change on my end? Not much! Basically, as I was already using buster in my /etc/apt/sources.list.d/ file, when I used apt-get update I got the following message:
1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 Get:1 http://security.</description></item><item><title>Cannot boot again `[SOLVED]`</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2019/03/2019-03-18_cannot_boot_again/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2019/03/2019-03-18_cannot_boot_again/</guid><description>Within the last two weeks, I ran into serious issues with my Debian machine. Two weeks ago, just as I described in a previous post, after some updates, I was not able to boot anymore. Given that everything was working very well before, I was convinced that this was an issue with GRUB2, but was not able to fix it despite a very demanding quest for a solution. I was so desperate that I decided to reinstall Debian (which turned out to be a good thing as it fixed minor issues I had with my hardware.</description></item><item><title>How to partition your external hard drive</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2018/12/2018-12-22_how_to_partition/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2018/12/2018-12-22_how_to_partition/</guid><description>Recently, I formatted an external hard drive and I created several partitions on it. For doing so, I used to very good tools:
Disks (gnome-disks); GParted (GNOME Partition Editor). Both tools are intuitive and makes your live really easy. You can also find good tutorials on line (e.g. looks at this answer on for a step by step GParted tutorial). I&amp;rsquo;ve just realized that GParted is actually the GUI for GNU Parted that will try next time I want to partition an hard drive (I&amp;rsquo;ve spotted this tuto 😄).</description></item><item><title>Cannot boot after upgrade on Debian Testing `[SOLVED]`</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2018/12/2018-12-17_cannot_boot_after/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2018/12/2018-12-17_cannot_boot_after/</guid><description>Yesterday, I upgraded some packages on my Debian machine as I regularly do (cannot remember the exact list) but when I rebooted the system, I was not able to access the file system anymore 😱.
It was the first time I had no clue about what I did wrong and also the first time I had no idea of what to do. Basically, every time I started my computer, I ended up on a page I had never seen before where I had only two options:</description></item><item><title>Make your computer talk!</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2018/10/2018-10-20_make_your_computer/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2018/10/2018-10-20_make_your_computer/</guid><description>When I was on MacOS, I really enjoyed the command say to make my macOS speak (another bad reason to procrastinate) and I was looking for a similar tool on Linux to make my Lenovo speak 😄. After a quick search, I found two software: spd-say and espeak. They both offer the same basic options, similar to the ones say provides on MacOS.
spd-say spd-say was already included in the set of tools I install with Debian so I checked out the documentation with man spd-say:</description></item><item><title>From one character encoding to another</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2018/10/2018-10-16_from_one_character/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2018/10/2018-10-16_from_one_character/</guid><description>Today I needed to check the character encoding of a file, I found this page that explains how to do this. Basically the command file will give you the info, for instance:
1 2 $ file example.md example.md: ASCII text options -i for --mime and -b for --brief will give:
1 2 $ file -bi example.md text/plain; charset=us-ascii I figured out that I needed to convert my file from one character encoding to another and so I used iconv.</description></item><item><title>How to count non-blank lines of a set of files?</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2018/09/2018-09-23_how_to_count/</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2018/09/2018-09-23_how_to_count/</guid><description>Yesterday, I was trying to find a way to count lines of a set of R files without comments nor empty lines and found this answer on stackoverflow:
1 cat R/* | sed &amp;#39;/^\s*#/d;/^\s*$/d&amp;#39; | wc -l Exactly what I needed! A few explanations are in order:
cat reads files sequentially; &amp;quot;|&amp;quot; is the the pipe operator; sed parses and transforms text; wc counts words, lines and more! Basically, counting lines of a file is done with the option -l of wc (option -m for characters, see man wc to learn more):</description></item><item><title>My Lenovo T470p</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2018/09/2018-09-14_my_lenovo_t470p/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2018/09/2018-09-14_my_lenovo_t470p/</guid><description>When I switched from MacOS to Debian, I had no idea what laptop to buy so I searched for some information on the Internet. As expected it was hard to find reliable sources of information among websites that are obviously not neutral. After a few hours on the net, I ended up buying a Lenovo ThinkPad T470p and installed Debian on, so far so good, very happy I made this choice.</description></item><item><title>Kernel 4.18</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2018/09/2018-09-12_kernel_4_18/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2018/09/2018-09-12_kernel_4_18/</guid><description>On Debian Testing today was a kernel update day! At 9:51am (Guelph time) I was still on kernel 4.17 😱
but at 9:53am, I was working with 4.18 🏆
By the way, the source code of the kernel is mirrored on Github, a repository without an issue section with a $\infty$ number of contributors 😂. Also, there is an exhaustive documentation available at https://www.kernel.org/doc/html/latest/.</description></item></channel></rss>