<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>SageMath on KevCaz's Website</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/tags/sagemath/</link><description>Recent content in SageMath on KevCaz's Website</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Content under CC0 1.0 Universal unless otherwise specified.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 18 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://kevcaz.github.io/tags/sagemath/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>SageMath version 8.6 on Debian Buster</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/sage/sagev8-6onbuster/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/sage/sagev8-6onbuster/</guid><description>This is a short note to follow up on a previous one where I reported the steps to install the latest release of Sage using the GitHub repository. At that time Sage version 8.3 was not available on Debian Buster but now version 8.6 is available on Buster! Given the set of dependencies of Sage, I guessed it was quite a challenge to pack it up, so 👏 to the relentless Debian package maintainers because thanks to them all I need to install Sage is:</description></item><item><title>More digits!</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/sage/getdigits/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/sage/getdigits/</guid><description>SageMath has tons of powerful features (I explain how to install the latest version on Debian buster in a previous note), one relatively simple and very handy function I&amp;rsquo;ve recently used is numerical_approx() (see the documentation) that returns (suspense = 0) a numerical approximation for any number of digits!
In my case, I was looking for a 40 digits approximation of 4*pi/(6+sqrt(38)). Using a programming language such as R, I would have had to tweak the printing format:</description></item><item><title>Building Sage 8.3 from sources on Debian Testing</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/sage/installsage/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/sage/installsage/</guid><description>Sage is a powerful mathematics software I use to do symbolic computation. Currently, there is no version available for Debian Testing, meaning you can either install the version available for the stable release or cherry pick the package available for Sid. Well I was not able to sudo apt-get the package for Stretch so I decided to use the same approach as I did for Julia (see this previous note). Basically, the sources of sage are mirrored on Github so one can clone the repository:</description></item></channel></rss>