<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>audio on KevCaz's Website</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/tags/audio/</link><description>Recent content in audio on KevCaz's Website</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Content under CC0 1.0 Universal unless otherwise specified.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sat, 24 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://kevcaz.github.io/tags/audio/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Concatenate audio files with FFmpeg</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/ffmpeg/concatenateaudiofiles/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/ffmpeg/concatenateaudiofiles/</guid><description>Yesterday I needed to combine several audio files and I figured out to do this with command lines. It was not as easy as I expected but I guess I underestimated how little I know about audio files! Anyway, below I explain what I did!
Preparing my audio files I had several audio files that I recorded with the voice recorder available on my phone. This application saves audio files as .</description></item><item><title>Even more internet radio stations</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/audio/audiophileisdown/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/audio/audiophileisdown/</guid><description>As mentioned in a previous post, I love listening to internet radios and a few months ago I discovered Audiophile radios which I&amp;rsquo;ve enjoyed very much for four months. But it looks like Audiophile is down now 😢 (hopefully just temporarily). So, today I spent some time looking for more internet radio stations that offer high quality streams and I found those valuable links:
listenlive.eu that lists radios for European countries, e.</description></item><item><title>More radio stations</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/audio/moreradio/</link><pubDate>Sun, 04 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/audio/moreradio/</guid><description>I am a radio listener and a podcast addict 📻! Yesterday, I spent some time adding more radio stations with Rhythmbox. I really love this software, it is simple and do everything I need, adding a new radio station with it was straightforward but it requires first to find the URLs of the radio stations to be added as there is no radio browser integrated (but have a look at radio-browser).</description></item><item><title>Use FFmpeg!</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/ffmpeg/useffmpeg/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/ffmpeg/useffmpeg/</guid><description>As mentioned on its website, FFmpeg is:
A complete, cross-platform solution to record, convert and stream audio and video.
FFmep is a powerful freeware, as mentioned on the Wikipedia page
FFmpeg includes libavcodec, an audio/video codec library used by many commercial and free software products, libavformat (Lavf),[6] an audio/video container mux and demux library, and the core ffmpeg command line program for transcoding multimedia files.
libavcodec is actually used in VLC a popular multimedia you may be familiar with.</description></item></channel></rss>