<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Raspberry Pi on KevCaz's Website</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/tags/raspberry-pi/</link><description>Recent content in Raspberry Pi on KevCaz's Website</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Content under CC0 1.0 Universal unless otherwise specified.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 23 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://kevcaz.github.io/tags/raspberry-pi/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Ansible playbook for setting up Nextcloud on a Raspberry Pi 3B</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2023/04/2023-04-23_ansible_playbook_for/</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2023/04/2023-04-23_ansible_playbook_for/</guid><description>&lt;p>I recently got a new SD card for my Raspberry Pi 3B, so I had to reinstall Nextcloud and I took the opportunity to create an &lt;a href="https://www.ansible.com/">Ansible&lt;/a> playbook for it. I basically went through the steps described in my previous note &lt;a href="https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2022/01/2022-01-05_nextcloud_server_on/" title="Go to this post">&amp;lsquo;Nextcloud server on a Raspberry Pi 3B&amp;rsquo;&lt;/a> and I turned them into a playbook. If you want to get an idea of what is Ansible, check out the &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ansible_(software)">Wikipedia article&lt;/a> and for what follows, let&amp;rsquo;s keep in mind the following:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Basic Git server on my Raspberry Pi</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2022/01/2022-01-11_basic_git_server/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2022/01/2022-01-11_basic_git_server/</guid><description>&lt;p>As mentioned in my &lt;a href="../../notes/rapsberrypi/nextcloud_server/">previous post&lt;/a>, I have recently started using my Raspberry Pi as a server and I decided to try to host a basic Git server.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As explained in the chapter &lt;a href="https://git-scm.com/book/en/v2/Git-on-the-Server-The-Protocols">&amp;ldquo;Git on the Server&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a> of Pro Git&lt;sup id="fnref:1">&lt;a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">1&lt;/a>&lt;/sup>, among other protocols, Git supports SSH and it is quite straightforward to setup a basic Git server via this protocol. As I can access my Raspberry Pi via ssh, I decided to give it a try! I first connected to it as user &lt;code>pi&lt;/code> (&lt;code>ssh pi@raspberry.local&lt;/code>), a user that is listed as a super user, and I created a new user: &lt;code>git&lt;/code> (this is one way suggested in Pro Git).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Nextcloud server on a Raspberry Pi 3B</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2022/01/2022-01-05_nextcloud_server_on/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2022/01/2022-01-05_nextcloud_server_on/</guid><description>&lt;p>I have already written elsewhere all the good that I think about Raspberry Pi. It is a fantastic project supported by a great community. I personally own a &lt;a href="../../notes/rapsberrypi/raspberrypi3b/">Rapsberry Pi model 3B&lt;/a> and so far I have been using it for several small projects. For more than a year I have been thinking about running some small services on my Raspberry Pi, but never took the time to set it up. I finally took Christmas time to do it and I started with &lt;a href="https://nextcloud.com/">NextCloud&lt;/a>. This post summarizes the different installation steps I went through to get a NextCloud server running on my Raspberry Pi. Note that I do not intend to provide a walk-through for the installation, I rather explain what needs to be done, give some commands and point to online documentation and tutorials. There are plenty of good tutorials available on line, notably the ones by &lt;a href="https://pimylifeup.com/">Pi My Life Up&lt;/a>, I don&amp;rsquo;t think they need to be duplicated!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>My Raspberry Pi 3B</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2019/07/2019-07-12_my_raspberry_pi/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2019/07/2019-07-12_my_raspberry_pi/</guid><description>&lt;p>Two years ago now, I bought myself a &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Raspberry_Pi">Raspberry Pi
3B&lt;/a> (back in 2015, I bought a model
2B and since June of this year, &lt;a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/products/raspberry-pi-4-model-b/">model 4B is
out&lt;/a> but has &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/7/10/20688655/raspberry-pi-4-usb-c-port-bug-e-marked-cables-audio-accessory-charging">some
issues&lt;/a>).
Even if don&amp;rsquo;t use it as much as I would like to, this small computer never
ceases to amaze me! The concept is awesome, the education goals are meaningful
and timely and the community is great, just check out the official website
&lt;a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/">https://www.raspberrypi.org/&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>