<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>font on KevCaz's Website</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/tags/font/</link><description>Recent content in font on KevCaz's Website</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Content under CC0 1.0 Universal unless otherwise specified.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://kevcaz.github.io/tags/font/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The fontawesome5 Latex package</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/latex/fontawesome5/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/latex/fontawesome5/</guid><description>Font Awesome is a very popular icon set used on websites to improve the visual grepping. For instance, whenever I point to a GitHub repository on my website I use &amp;lt;i class=&amp;quot;fa fa-github&amp;quot; aria-hidden=&amp;quot;true&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/i&amp;gt; to add the following icon that indicates, to people familiar with GitHub, the kind of content the link points to.
Visual grepping is somewhat powerful and months ago I started to use this icon set in my CV (see KevCaz/CV_latex) via the fontawesome Latex package that was maintained by Xavier Danaux (see xdanaux/fontawesome-latex).</description></item><item><title>My programming fonts!</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/font/font4code/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/font/font4code/</guid><description>Given that I spend most of my working time on a code editor (including to write papers), I regard the choice of the font as quite important. To me, a programming font must be monospaced (programming without a monospaced font is quite challenging) and appeal to me (a matter of readability and aesthetic I guess).
There are tons of fonts nowadays and it is quite easy to create your own (see for instance fontstruc), so the choice is wide!</description></item></channel></rss>