<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>UEFI on KevCaz's Website</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/tags/uefi/</link><description>Recent content in UEFI on KevCaz's Website</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Content under CC0 1.0 Universal unless otherwise specified.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://kevcaz.github.io/tags/uefi/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Cannot boot again `[SOLVED]`</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/linux/cannotbootagain/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/linux/cannotbootagain/</guid><description>Within the last two weeks, I ran into serious issues with my Debian machine. Two weeks ago, just as I described in a previous post, after some updates, I was not able to boot anymore. Given that everything was working very well before, I was convinced that this was an issue with GRUB2, but was not able to fix it despite a very demanding quest for a solution. I was so desperate that I decided to reinstall Debian (which turned out to be a good thing as it fixed minor issues I had with my hardware.</description></item><item><title>Cannot boot after upgrade on Debian Testing `[SOLVED]`</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/linux/cannotboot/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/linux/cannotboot/</guid><description>Yesterday, I upgraded some packages on my Debian machine as I regularly do (cannot remember the exact list) but when I rebooted the system, I was not able to access the file system anymore 😱.
It was the first time I had no clue about what I did wrong and also the first time I had no idea of what to do. Basically, every time I started my computer, I ended up on a page I had never seen before where I had only two options:</description></item></channel></rss>