<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Website on KevCaz's Website</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/tags/website/</link><description>Recent content in Website on KevCaz's Website</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Content under CC0 1.0 Universal unless otherwise specified.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 29 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://kevcaz.github.io/tags/website/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Time to talk about this website!</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2021/01/2021-01-29_time_to_talk/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2021/01/2021-01-29_time_to_talk/</guid><description>For this 100th SilicoNote/post, I have decided to share some notes about this website : its story and a few details about how I built the last version of it.
The short story behind my website As far as I remembered, I have built 5 different versions of my personal website. I decided to get a website when I was doing my PhD, back in 2014 (not a 100% about sure about the timeline), in order to share some of my work.</description></item><item><title>Deploy a pkgdown website on gh-pages manually</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2020/04/2020-04-12_deploy_a_pkgdown/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2020/04/2020-04-12_deploy_a_pkgdown/</guid><description>This is another note about deploying a pkgdown1 website with Travis on gh-pages. I had previously used the package travis but I was recently interested in doing so manually. Fortunately, I found this very helpful walk-through by Gábor Csárdi2. I used it and it worked well for a while, but at some point I had an issue with the deployment part (still not sure why), so I changed it. Instead of using the following config3</description></item><item><title>Deploy a pkgdown on gh-pages</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2019/10/2019-10-22_deploy_a_pkgdown/</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2019/10/2019-10-22_deploy_a_pkgdown/</guid><description>There are three ways to deploy a website on your GitHub pages :
using the gh-pages; using the folder docs on your master branch; using the master branch. I frequently use the GitHub pages to deploy the pkgdown websites I create for my R packages. For a while, I was using the docs/ folder where the website is generated by default. But I figured that this way has two main drawbacks:</description></item><item><title>My Hugo shortcode for video</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2018/09/2018-09-27_my_hugo_shortcode/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2018/09/2018-09-27_my_hugo_shortcode/</guid><description>Shortcodes are among my favorite features in Hugo. As I am currently writing several notes a week that often include small screencasts, I thought that the time had come for me to create my own screencast shortcode. Here it is:
1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 &amp;lt;center&amp;gt; &amp;lt;video width=&amp;#39; {{ if .Get &amp;#34;width&amp;#34; }} {{ .Get &amp;#34;width&amp;#34; }} {{ else }} 100% {{ end }}&amp;#39; controls&amp;gt; &amp;lt;source src=&amp;#34;{{ .</description></item></channel></rss>