<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Thunderbird on KevCaz's Website</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/tags/thunderbird/</link><description>Recent content in Thunderbird on KevCaz's Website</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Content under CC0 1.0 Universal unless otherwise specified.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 30 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://kevcaz.github.io/tags/thunderbird/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Thunderbird Debian package has already been patched!</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/mozilla/thunderbird78-11-0-2/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/mozilla/thunderbird78-11-0-2/</guid><description>In my previous note, I reported major issues with Thunderbird 78.11.0-1. As it turned out, it was an actual bug that has been reported. Shortly after the report, a work around has been proposed, and the new patch uploaded last Sunday (2021/06/29) solves all the issues I encountered. So everything is back to normal!
1 2 3 4 5 6 $ apt-cache show thunderbird | head -n 5 Package: thunderbird Version: 1:78.</description></item><item><title>What is wrong with Thunderbird?</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/mozilla/thunderbird78-11-0-1/</link><pubDate>Sat, 19 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/mozilla/thunderbird78-11-0-1/</guid><description>Few days ago, as I was trying to refresh my emails, I realize that Thunderbird (Thunderbird 78.11.0) was no longer able to retrieved my mails from Gmail. I tried to understand what was the problem but I wasn&amp;rsquo;t able to figure it out. After a while, I decided to uninstall Thunderbird and reinstall it. Things just got worst I couldn&amp;rsquo;t set any of my email accounts. For my Gmail, I tried to use OAuth2, as it is recommended (it used to work for me), but the identification protocol did not work: instead of getting the Gmail interface to login, I got an error message pointing out a lack of security (NS_ERROR_NET_INADEQUATE_SECURITY)&amp;hellip; As I did not understand why, I decided to stop speeding time on trying to find the origin of the problem.</description></item><item><title>Writing your emails in Markdown with Thunderbird 78</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/mozilla/markdowninthunderbird/</link><pubDate>Sun, 31 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/mozilla/markdowninthunderbird/</guid><description>For more than three years now, I have been written most of my emails in Markdown! How so? I have been using the Markdown Here add-on for Thunderbird. As explained in the &amp;lsquo;features&amp;rsquo; page of the extension website:
Markdown Here is an extension for Chrome, Firefox, Safari, Opera, Thunderbird, and Postbox. With it, you can write email in Markdown, and then click a button (or context menu item, or use a hotkey) to render the email into good-looking, fully formatted text (HTML, technically).</description></item><item><title>Thunderbird v60.3.0 solves them all!</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/mozilla/thunderbird60-3/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/mozilla/thunderbird60-3/</guid><description>As I mentioned in a previous note, when I installed the version 60.0-3 of Thunderbird I was no longer able to write new emails and so I had to downgrade to v.52.9.1. Since that time, things have gotten worst as I was no longer able to get hyperlinks opening the corresponding page in my web browser 😱. I did not look for a fix, I simply coped with it waiting for an update.</description></item><item><title>Back to Thunderbird 52.9.1!</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/mozilla/olderthuderbirdversion/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/mozilla/olderthuderbirdversion/</guid><description>Recently, Firefox 60 and Thunderbird 60 were made available for Debian Testing and I installed them. While I was and still am happy with Firefox 60, when I tried Thunderbird I had some issues&amp;hellip; Basically, I was not able to send a message and one of my favorite add-on, Markdown-Here, was not available for this version 😢. So, I needed to get the previous version back. I searched for an answer and found this one, very helpful!</description></item></channel></rss>