<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Zenodo on KevCaz's Website</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/tags/zenodo/</link><description>Recent content in Zenodo on KevCaz's Website</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Content under CC0 1.0 Universal unless otherwise specified.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 13 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://kevcaz.github.io/tags/zenodo/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Releasing the research compendium for our Labmnivory paper</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/econotes/2021/publish_compendium/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/econotes/2021/publish_compendium/</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="mega-this-post-was-first-published-on-mccannlabca">&amp;#x1f4e3; This post was first published on &lt;a href="https://mccannlab.ca/post/2021/12/13/releasing-the-research-compendium-for-our-labmnivory-paper/">mccannlab.ca&lt;/a>.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Good news everyone! This week, our &amp;ldquo;Labmnivory&amp;rdquo; paper led by &lt;a href="https://www.researchgate.net/profile/Marie-Gutgesell">Marie Gutgesell&lt;/a> has been accepted in &lt;a href="https://academic.oup.com/bioscience">Bioscience&lt;/a>. Therefore, the time has come to release the code we promised explicitly in the manuscript.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Code for theoretical investigations will be made available on GitHub and archive on Zenodo upon manuscript acceptance.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>For &lt;a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/books/NBK547546/">reproducibility&lt;/a>&amp;rsquo;s sake, we&amp;rsquo;ve structured our &lt;a href="https://julialang.org/">Julia&lt;/a> scripts as a &lt;a href="https://research-compendium.science/">research compendium&lt;/a> which so far has been &lt;a href="https://github.com/McCannLab/Labmnivory/">hosted on GitHub&lt;/a>, in a private repository. The goal of this post is to go over the different steps to have our research compendium archived on &lt;a href="https://zenodo.org/">Zenodo&lt;/a>. Having the full set of scripts used to obtain the results of a given study archived publicly somewhere doesn&amp;rsquo;t hurt! If you skip this step, you may end up in a situation where someone is trying to reproduce your results and is failing at it&amp;hellip; In such case, it is most likely that you will feel very bad not being able to find the original code!&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>