<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>latex on KevCaz's Website</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/tags/latex/</link><description>Recent content in latex on KevCaz's Website</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Content under CC0 1.0 Universal unless otherwise specified.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://kevcaz.github.io/tags/latex/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The fontawesome5 Latex package</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/latex/fontawesome5/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/latex/fontawesome5/</guid><description>Font Awesome is a very popular icon set used on websites to improve the visual grepping. For instance, whenever I point to a GitHub repository on my website I use &amp;lt;i class=&amp;quot;fa fa-github&amp;quot; aria-hidden=&amp;quot;true&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/i&amp;gt; to add the following icon that indicates, to people familiar with GitHub, the kind of content the link points to.
Visual grepping is somewhat powerful and months ago I started to use this icon set in my CV (see KevCaz/CV_latex) via the fontawesome Latex package that was maintained by Xavier Danaux (see xdanaux/fontawesome-latex).</description></item><item><title>Merging .bib files with bibtool</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/latex/bibtools/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/latex/bibtools/</guid><description>As researchers, we sometimes write manuscripts collectively and remotely in LaTeX (or in a lightweight markup languages that is converted into LaTeX at some point). In such case, it is quite useful to let co-authors edit their own bib file in order to store the references included in the part of the manuscript they are editing. One way to deal with several bib files is to merge them into one bib file before compiling the final document to pdf.</description></item><item><title>A few more LaTeX symbols</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/latex/newsybols/</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/latex/newsybols/</guid><description>Yesterday I learned 3 more LaTeX symbols while I was reviewing a paper 😺:
an equivalence symbol: $\equiv$ $\equiv$, use \xi not $\ksi$ for $\xi$, $\widehat{}$ for estimators (in statistics), for instance: $\widehat{\xi}$. Also, it was a good opportunity to remind myself that when looking for a specific symbol, one can always google an approximate description of the it, or one can use Detexify an extremely helpful LaTeX handwritten symbol recognition system!</description></item></channel></rss>