<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>VSCodium on KevCaz's Website</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/tags/vscodium/</link><description>Recent content in VSCodium on KevCaz's Website</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Content under CC0 1.0 Universal unless otherwise specified.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 21 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://kevcaz.github.io/tags/vscodium/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Installing Spell Right on VSCodium v1.49</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2020/09/2020-09-21_installing_spell_right/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2020/09/2020-09-21_installing_spell_right/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://vscodium.com/">VSCodium&lt;/a> is an automatic &amp;ldquo;clean&amp;rdquo; build of &lt;a href="https://code.visualstudio.com/">Virtual Studio Code (VSCode)&lt;/a>,
i.e. a build without the Microsoft touch. VSCode (thus VSCodium) is very powerful, has a tons of features and its development is very dynamic, so I am always keeping an eye on what&amp;rsquo;s new with VSCode even though I am still using &lt;a href="https://atom.io/">Atom&lt;/a> more frequently.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When &lt;a href="../../notes/hardware/setup_bullseye">I set up Bullseye on my ThinkPad&lt;/a> I installed the latest version of VSCodium and when I looked up for my favorite extensions, I realized that
many extensions were actually missing. After a quick search, I figured that, since version 1.46,
&lt;a href="https://marketplace.visualstudio.com/">Visual Studio Marketplace&lt;/a> is no longer added as an extension gallery in VSCodium. Rather, VSCodium relies on
&lt;a href="https://open-vsx.org">Open VSX Registry&lt;/a> (see also &lt;a href="https://www.gitpod.io/blog/open-vsx/">the article about Open VSX on Gitpod&lt;/a>) but the &lt;a href="https://github.com/eclipse/openvsx/wiki/Publishing-Extensions">publication on this registry&lt;/a> represents extra step for developers, thus the missing applications. This includes &lt;a href="https://github.com/bartosz-antosik/vscode-spellright">Spell Right&lt;/a>
that, a very handful spell checker, that is only available on &lt;a href="https://marketplace.visualstudio.com/">https://marketplace.visualstudio.com/&lt;/a>. Fortunately, the VSCodium team has listed &lt;a href="https://github.com/VSCodium/vscodium/blob/master/DOCS.md#extensions-marketplace">several ways to deal with this issue&lt;/a> (including a way to add Visual Studio Marketplace as a registry). I opted for installing Spell Right from the &lt;code>.vsix&lt;/code>. To do so, I went on the extension&amp;rsquo;s page on &lt;a href="https://marketplace.visualstudio.com/items?itemName=ban.spellright">Marketplace&lt;/a> and clicked on &lt;kbd>Download Extension&lt;/kbd>,
then I used the following command:&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>