<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Setup on KevCaz's Website</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/tags/setup/</link><description>Recent content in Setup on KevCaz's Website</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Content under CC0 1.0 Universal unless otherwise specified.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 03 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://kevcaz.github.io/tags/setup/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Debian Bookworm setup -- update</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2023/02/2023-02-03_debian_bookworm_setup/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2023/02/2023-02-03_debian_bookworm_setup/</guid><description>I recently lent someone my Lenovo T470p and when I got it back, I decided to install Debian back on it (I installed Ubuntu 22.04 to make it easier to use for a non-Linux user). I went through all the installation seamlessly, but I was not able to have the wifi working. I knew it was related to firmware-iwlwifi, but I was unable to install it. As it turned out, the package was not available for bookworm (found this but looking at https://packages.</description></item><item><title>Debian Bookworm setup</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2022/05/2022-05-22_debian_bookworm_setup/</link><pubDate>Sun, 22 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2022/05/2022-05-22_debian_bookworm_setup/</guid><description>I recently decided to re-install my computer and I took the opportunity to create a gist that includes light version of my Debian 11 set-up, i.e. all the tools I used the most. Once again during the install (I use a Debian weekly build installation image) did not keep things light as I let several pieces of software be installed during the setup (e.g. LibreOffice, Inkscape). So here goes the 4th version of my bash script to install Debian on my Lenovo T470p &amp;#x2b07;&amp;#xfe0f;.</description></item><item><title>Use flatpak!</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2021/02/2021-02-10_use_flatpak/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2021/02/2021-02-10_use_flatpak/</guid><description>Two days ago, I was attempting to install GNOME Fractal but apt-get couldn&amp;rsquo;t find it&amp;hellip; Cause it&amp;rsquo;s a GNOME application I thought is was unexpected, so I checked the README file. It turned out that the developers actually suggest to install their app with either Snap or Flatpak. As I knew about the former and hadn&amp;rsquo;t heard about the later, I decided to install flatpak.
1 $ apt install flatpak I then used flatpak to install Fractal.</description></item><item><title>Migrating from Buster to Bullseye</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2020/09/2020-09-18_migrating_from_buster/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2020/09/2020-09-18_migrating_from_buster/</guid><description>In July 2019, Buster became the stable release of Debian and the Bullseye became de facto the new testing distribution. After spending almost 2 years on Buster, I decided last week that it was time to migrate to Bullseye.
Backing up I frequently backup my files (so far with a simple bash function that copies them to my external hard drive). Plus, I also have a repository, dotfiles, where I stored my configuration files (the ones I can share).</description></item><item><title>Dual Boot MacOS-Ubuntu</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2019/07/2019-07-16_dual_boot_macos/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2019/07/2019-07-16_dual_boot_macos/</guid><description>Context I must say that I have been quite unhappy with my old Mac Book Pro (mid 2012) for almost a year now. IIRC, I got it early 2013 and it served me well during my PhD but now it is kind of slow &amp;#x1f422; and often behaves weirdly on boot. Last weekend fir instance, I got a nasty black screen on boot &amp;#x1f631;. Turns out it happens frequently and there are no less than four different solutions to this issue &amp;#x1f631; (in my case, emptying the PRAM did the job)&amp;hellip; Windows, MacOS, blue screen, black screen, yunno&amp;hellip; I found having these issues actually rather worrisome because I care about my computer, I update it frequently and I&amp;rsquo;m actually capable of solving this kind of issues, so WTF?</description></item><item><title>My Raspberry Pi 3B</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2019/07/2019-07-12_my_raspberry_pi/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2019/07/2019-07-12_my_raspberry_pi/</guid><description>Two years ago now, I bought myself a Raspberry Pi 3B (back in 2015, I bought a model 2B and since June of this year, model 4B is out but has some issues). Even if don&amp;rsquo;t use it as much as I would like to, this small computer never ceases to amaze me! The concept is awesome, the education goals are meaningful and timely and the community is great, just check out the official website https://www.</description></item><item><title>My Lenovo T470p</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2018/09/2018-09-14_my_lenovo_t470p/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2018/09/2018-09-14_my_lenovo_t470p/</guid><description>When I switched from MacOS to Debian, I had no idea what laptop to buy so I searched for some information on the Internet. As expected it was hard to find reliable sources of information among websites that are obviously not neutral. After a few hours on the net, I ended up buying a Lenovo ThinkPad T470p and installed Debian on, so far so good, very happy I made this choice.</description></item></channel></rss>