<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Rcites on KevCaz's Website</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/tags/rcites/</link><description>Recent content in Rcites on KevCaz's Website</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Content under CC0 1.0 Universal unless otherwise specified.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 19 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://kevcaz.github.io/tags/rcites/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>rcites 1.3.0</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2023/02/2023-02-19_rcites_1_3/</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2023/02/2023-02-19_rcites_1_3/</guid><description>rcites 1.3.0 is now available on CRAN &amp;#x1f389;. This was mainly a maintenance release following up on a recent issue in vcr (see Overview of fixes for upcoming v1.2) but I also took the opportunity to improve the set_token() function. Now the user has up to five attempts to set up the token when set_token() is called, after that error is triggered (previously the error was triggered after the first failed attempt).</description></item><item><title>R packages rmangal and rcites updated on CRAN</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2021/11/2021-11-25_r_packages_rmangal/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2021/11/2021-11-25_r_packages_rmangal/</guid><description>Over the past few weeks, I took some time to review the unit tests for rmangal and rcites. Both packages are R clients for web APIs:
rmangal allows users to search ecological interactions available in the Mangal database; rcites allows users to query the Species+ database by leveraging the Speciesplus/CITES Checklist API. One of the main challenges with such packages is to not get archived on CRAN &amp;#x1f631;! rmangal was actually archived a year ago for policy violation on internet access, and so one of my main goals was to get it back on CRAN.</description></item><item><title>rcites code coverage dropped to 0</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2018/10/2018-10-09_rcites_code_coverage/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2018/10/2018-10-09_rcites_code_coverage/</guid><description>We (a couple of colleagues and myself) are currently finishing a major release for our R package rcites. After adding the latest feature I have been working on via a pull request, I messed up with my local master branch and overwrite/delete some files &amp;#x1f620;. I thought it was not a big deal as all of them were files created/edited when the package is built (well, I thought so). But after the very next push, the code coverage weirdly dropped to zero &amp;#x1f631;.</description></item></channel></rss>