<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>publication on KevCaz's Website</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/tags/publication/</link><description>Recent content in publication on KevCaz's Website</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Content under CC0 1.0 Universal unless otherwise specified.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 20 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://kevcaz.github.io/tags/publication/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Homogenization of freshwater lakes</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/econotes/2019/homogenontario/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/econotes/2019/homogenontario/</guid><description>This was originally posted on https://mccannlab.ca/post/2019/09/20/homogenization-of-freshwater-lakes/
English version 🇬🇧 What happened to fish communities in Ontario lakes over the last few decades? We have been relentlessly looking for answers to this question! Indeed, we did our best to determine whether global change has affected those communities over the last 40 years. It turns out that fish communities in Ontario lakes are pretty different from what they were, but climate change does not explain those changes 💥!</description></item><item><title>Towards an integrated theory of biogeography</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/econotes/2016/towards-an-integrated-theory-of-biogeography/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/econotes/2016/towards-an-integrated-theory-of-biogeography/</guid><description>Dominique Gravel, Nicolas Mouquet, David Mouillot and I have recently published a paper in Ecography entitled &amp;lsquo;On the integration of biotic interaction and environmental constraints at the biogeographical scale&amp;rsquo; where we develop some ideas about how ecological interactions and abiotic factors must be taken together into account to better predict species&amp;rsquo; distribution. As suggested during the editing process, we wrote a blog post for Ecography that summarizes our paper. I think blog posts are an useful way to promote one&amp;rsquo;s work and also a good compromise between reading the abstract and reading the entire paper.</description></item></channel></rss>