<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>MacOS on KevCaz's Website</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/tags/macos/</link><description>Recent content in MacOS on KevCaz's Website</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Content under CC0 1.0 Universal unless otherwise specified.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://kevcaz.github.io/tags/macos/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Dual Boot MacOS-Ubuntu</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2019/07/2019-07-16_dual_boot_macos/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2019/07/2019-07-16_dual_boot_macos/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="context">Context&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>I must say that I have been quite unhappy with my old Mac Book Pro (mid 2012)
for almost a year now. IIRC, I got it early 2013 and it served me well during my
PhD but now it is kind of slow &amp;#x1f422; and often behaves weirdly on boot. Last
weekend fir instance, I got a nasty black screen on boot &amp;#x1f631;. Turns out it
happens frequently and there are no less than &lt;a href="http://osxdaily.com/2014/11/22/fix-macbook-pro-booting-black-screen/">four different solutions to this
issue
&amp;#x1f631;&lt;/a>
(in my case, emptying the PRAM did the job)&amp;hellip; Windows, MacOS, blue screen,
black screen, yunno&amp;hellip; I found having these issues actually rather worrisome
because I care about my computer, I update it frequently and I&amp;rsquo;m actually
capable of solving this kind of issues, so WTF? This whole situation makes me
wonder what people unable to deal with this kind of problem would do&amp;hellip; My guess
is they would go to an fancy Apple store to either get it fixed &amp;#x1f4b0; or
get a new shinny Mac &amp;#x1f4b0;&amp;#x1f4b0;&amp;#x1f4b0;! Anyway, as the time went on, I started to feel frustrated and as I was not a big fan of &lt;a href="https://www.apple.com/ca/fr/macos/mojave/">MacOS Mojave&lt;/a> (it brings nothing I need and I haven&amp;rsquo;t noted any improvement). Given this I decided:&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>