<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>hunspell on KevCaz's Website</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/tags/hunspell/</link><description>Recent content in hunspell on KevCaz's Website</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Content under CC0 1.0 Universal unless otherwise specified.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 21 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://kevcaz.github.io/tags/hunspell/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Installing Spell Right on VSCodium v1.49</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/vscodium/install_spell_right/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/vscodium/install_spell_right/</guid><description>VSCodium is an automatic &amp;ldquo;clean&amp;rdquo; build of Virtual Studio Code (VSCode), i.e. a build without the Microsoft touch. VSCode (thus VSCodium) is very powerful, has a tons of features and its development is very dynamic, so I am always keeping an eye on what&amp;rsquo;s new with VSCode even though I am still using Atom more frequently.
When I set up Bullseye on my ThinkPad I installed the latest version of VSCodium and when I looked up for my favorite extensions, I realized that many extensions were actually missing.</description></item><item><title>More than one langage with spell-check</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/atom/twolocales/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/atom/twolocales/</guid><description>I spend most on my coding and writing time on Atom and as I write in both English and French I use two dictionaries with spell-check. Well, it actually took me a while to understand how to use two different locales on my Debian machine simply because I was lazy enough to not read the README on the Github repository of spell-check. Out of curiosity, I checked out what hunspell is (note that the project is hosted on Github) and then I checked the dictionaries currently installed on my device:</description></item></channel></rss>