<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>code on KevCaz's Website</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/tags/code/</link><description>Recent content in code on KevCaz's Website</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Content under CC0 1.0 Universal unless otherwise specified.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 17 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://kevcaz.github.io/tags/code/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Never too late to publish your code!</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/econotes/2020/biogeonet/</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/econotes/2020/biogeonet/</guid><description>Since 2017, for every article I work on, I now do my best to release the code I used to obtain the results presented therein (see my research compendia in the software section). In my humble opinion, this is the least I can do cause the numerical part of a study (often a large part of my work) is relatively easy to reproduce, though it requires some time to master the tools to do so.</description></item><item><title>Count your lines of code with `cloc`</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/cli/cloc/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/cli/cloc/</guid><description>I recently found out about cloc that is a very useful command line tool written in Perl that &amp;ldquo;counts blank lines, comment lines, and physical lines of source code in many programming languages&amp;rdquo;1. Let&amp;rsquo;s see how it works 👁.
The first step is to install cloc, there are several ways to do so, as a Debian user (Debian Buster) all I had to do was to use apt-get:
1 $ apt-get install cloc Once installed, cloc can be call in a Terminal like so: cloc path/to/file_or_folder.</description></item><item><title>My programming fonts!</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/font/font4code/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/font/font4code/</guid><description>Given that I spend most of my working time on a code editor (including to write papers), I regard the choice of the font as quite important. To me, a programming font must be monospaced (programming without a monospaced font is quite challenging) and appeal to me (a matter of readability and aesthetic I guess).
There are tons of fonts nowadays and it is quite easy to create your own (see for instance fontstruc), so the choice is wide!</description></item></channel></rss>