<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Internet Radio on KevCaz's Website</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/tags/internet-radio/</link><description>Recent content in Internet Radio on KevCaz's Website</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Content under CC0 1.0 Universal unless otherwise specified.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://kevcaz.github.io/tags/internet-radio/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Even more internet radio stations</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2019/03/2019-03-15_even_more_internet/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2019/03/2019-03-15_even_more_internet/</guid><description>&lt;p>As mentioned in a &lt;a href="../../notes/audio/moreradio/">previous post&lt;/a>, I love listening to internet radios and a few months ago I discovered Audiophile radios which I&amp;rsquo;ve enjoyed very much for four months. But it looks like Audiophile is down now &amp;#x1f622; (hopefully just temporarily). So, today I spent some time looking for more internet radio stations that offer high quality streams and I found those valuable links:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="http://www.listenlive.eu/index.html">listenlive.eu&lt;/a> that lists radios for European countries, e.g. for France &amp;#x1f1eb;&amp;#x1f1f7;, you can get a list of streams &lt;a href="http://www.listenlive.eu/france.html">here&lt;/a>;&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://absoluteradio.co.uk/">Absolute radio&lt;/a> that offers radio for different music eras at several quality levels;&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="http://intranature.com/">intraNature&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://www.thezenlounge.jp/">The Zen Lounge&lt;/a> for great ambient music.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Note that I found them looking on the internet, especially on &lt;a href="https://www.internet-radio.com/">InternetRadio&lt;/a> where I previously discovered Audiophile radios. And if you want to quickly get all the streams I currently listening to, look the list of URL of Internet radio stations below &amp;#x2b07;&amp;#xfe0f;.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>More radio stations</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2018/11/2018-11-04_more_radio_stations/</link><pubDate>Sun, 04 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/notes/2018/11/2018-11-04_more_radio_stations/</guid><description>&lt;p>I am a radio listener and a podcast addict &amp;#x1f4fb;! Yesterday, I spent some time adding more
radio stations with &lt;a href="https://wiki.gnome.org/Apps/Rhythmbox">Rhythmbox&lt;/a>. I
really love this software, it is simple and do everything I need, adding a new
radio station with it was straightforward but it requires first to find the
URLs of the radio stations to be added as there is no radio browser integrated
(but have a look at &lt;a href="https://github.com/fossfreedom/radio-browser">radio-browser&lt;/a>).
So to be more accurate, I spent some time finding where to find such URLs!&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>