<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>&lt;i class='fab fa-canadian-maple-leaf'>&lt;/i> EcoNotes on KevCaz's Website</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/econotes/</link><description>Recent content in &lt;i class='fab fa-canadian-maple-leaf'>&lt;/i> EcoNotes on KevCaz's Website</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Content under CC0 1.0 Universal unless otherwise specified.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 13 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://kevcaz.github.io/econotes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Releasing the research compendium for our Labmnivory paper</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/econotes/2021/publish_compendium/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/econotes/2021/publish_compendium/</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="mega-this-post-was-first-published-on-mccannlabca">&amp;#x1f4e3; This post was first published on &lt;a href="https://mccannlab.ca/post/2021/12/13/releasing-the-research-compendium-for-our-labmnivory-paper/">mccannlab.ca&lt;/a>.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Good news everyone! This week, our &amp;ldquo;Labmnivory&amp;rdquo; paper led by &lt;a href="https://www.researchgate.net/profile/Marie-Gutgesell">Marie Gutgesell&lt;/a> has been accepted in &lt;a href="https://academic.oup.com/bioscience">Bioscience&lt;/a>. Therefore, the time has come to release the code we promised explicitly in the manuscript.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Code for theoretical investigations will be made available on GitHub and archive on Zenodo upon manuscript acceptance.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>For &lt;a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/books/NBK547546/">reproducibility&lt;/a>&amp;rsquo;s sake, we&amp;rsquo;ve structured our &lt;a href="https://julialang.org/">Julia&lt;/a> scripts as a &lt;a href="https://research-compendium.science/">research compendium&lt;/a> which so far has been &lt;a href="https://github.com/McCannLab/Labmnivory/">hosted on GitHub&lt;/a>, in a private repository. The goal of this post is to go over the different steps to have our research compendium archived on &lt;a href="https://zenodo.org/">Zenodo&lt;/a>. Having the full set of scripts used to obtain the results of a given study archived publicly somewhere doesn&amp;rsquo;t hurt! If you skip this step, you may end up in a situation where someone is trying to reproduce your results and is failing at it&amp;hellip; In such case, it is most likely that you will feel very bad not being able to find the original code!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>On the sensitivity of food webs to multiple stressors</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/econotes/2021/mulistressors/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/econotes/2021/mulistressors/</guid><description>&lt;p>Our latest work&lt;sup id="fnref:1">&lt;a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">1&lt;/a>&lt;/sup> led by &lt;a href="https://www.researchgate.net/profile/David-Beauchesne">David Beauchesne&lt;/a> is out since yesterday in &lt;a href="https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/abs/10.1111/ele.13841?campaign=wolearlyview">Ecology Letters&lt;/a> &amp;#x1f973;! This paper introduces a framework that allows the exploration of the impact of multiple stressors on food webs.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In the Anthropocene, human activities impact species is various ways. Multiple
stressors frameworks attempt to account for their diversity and their joint
effects (stressors may have antagonistic or synergistic effects). Most of such
frameworks (if not all) are species-based, meaning that they account for the
sensitivity of species to the stressors and the intensity of the stressor (e.g.,
Halpern 2019&lt;sup id="fnref:2">&lt;a href="#fn:2" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">2&lt;/a>&lt;/sup>) but not for the ecological relationships among species.
However, it is a truism to say that species are not independent and therefore
approaches that neglect ecological interactions may lead to inaccurate
predictions. That is why we&amp;rsquo;ve put a lot of efforts in combining food web
concepts in a multiple stressors approach.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Corals, Algae, Fish and Humans</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/econotes/2021/corals/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/econotes/2021/corals/</guid><description>&lt;p>As I am jumping into a new project on coral reefs in the Carribeans, I thought it would make great sense for me to spend some time to get some basic ideas about corals, what&amp;rsquo;s currently threatening them and what are the consequences of the worldwide decline of coral cover.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="some-basic-knowledge-about-corals">Some basic knowledge about corals&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.icriforum.org/about-coral-reefs/what-are-corals/">Corals&lt;/a> are &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cnidaria">cnidarians&lt;/a>, Cnidaria is a phylum that includes hydrae (Hydrozoa), jellyfish (Medusozoa), among others. Corals form colonies made of clones called &lt;a href="https://bit.ly/3iVRRfY">polyps&lt;/a> that are linked by a tissue called coenenchyme&lt;sup id="fnref:1">&lt;a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">1&lt;/a>&lt;/sup>. The process of forming a new clone is called budding (or fragmentation). Corals also reproduce sexually and this is how new colonies are created. Just as the other cnidarians, corals have cnidocytes that are cells that produce &lt;a href="https://simple.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cnida">cnidae&lt;/a> (or cnidocysts) which are large and complex organelles&lt;sup id="fnref:2">&lt;a href="#fn:2" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">2&lt;/a>&lt;/sup> that allow polyps to catch/kill their prey (zooplankton).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Co-occurrence, not interaction!</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/econotes/2020/coocnotinter/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/econotes/2020/coocnotinter/</guid><description>&lt;p>This note is a short comment on the paper &lt;a href="https://www.researchgate.net/profile/F_Guillaume_Blanchet">Guillaume Blanchet&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="http://ielab.recherche.usherbrooke.ca/">Dominique Gravel&lt;/a> and I recently published in &lt;a href="https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/14610248">Ecology Letters&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>

&lt;h1 id="what-did-we-do">What did we do?&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>We basically went over 7 arguments to explain why the information in
co-occurrence cannot be taken as a proxy for ecological interactions. Before I
quickly review the list of arguments, there are two points worth mentioning
about those arguments. First, &lt;strong>we are discussing the inference of static
ecological networks from occurrence data with an optional set of abiotic
variables&lt;/strong>. Second, we have not tried to be exhaustive nor have we tried to
find the minimal set of the most general arguments. Rather, we opted for strong
arguments that would speak to a wide range of ecologists, which means that:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Never too late to publish your code!</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/econotes/2020/biogeonet/</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/econotes/2020/biogeonet/</guid><description>&lt;p>Since 2017, for every article I work on, I now do my best to release the code I
used to obtain the results presented therein (see my research compendia in the
&lt;a href="../software/">software section&lt;/a>). In my humble opinion, this is the least I can
do cause the numerical part of a study (often a large part of my work) is
relatively easy to reproduce, though it requires some time to master the tools
to do so. As I now perceived reproducibility of my work as a duty, I felt guilty regarding a paper I published back in 2015.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Homogenization of freshwater lakes</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/econotes/2019/homogenontario/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/econotes/2019/homogenontario/</guid><description>&lt;p>This was originally posted on &lt;a href="https://mccannlab.ca/post/2019/09/20/homogenization-of-freshwater-lakes/">https://mccannlab.ca/post/2019/09/20/homogenization-of-freshwater-lakes/&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="english-version-uk">English version &amp;#x1f1ec;&amp;#x1f1e7;&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>What happened to fish communities in Ontario lakes over the last few decades? We
have been relentlessly looking for answers to this question! Indeed, we did our
best to determine whether global change has affected those communities over the
last 40 years. It turns out that fish communities in Ontario lakes are pretty
different from what they were, but climate change does not explain those changes
&amp;#x1f4a5;! But, but… how can we say that? Well, that&amp;rsquo;s the topic of this post &amp;#x1f609;.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Towards an integrated theory of biogeography</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/econotes/2016/towards-an-integrated-theory-of-biogeography/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/econotes/2016/towards-an-integrated-theory-of-biogeography/</guid><description>&lt;p>Dominique Gravel, Nicolas Mouquet, David Mouillot and I have recently published a paper in &lt;a href="http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/10.1111/(ISSN)1600-0587">&lt;em>Ecography&lt;/em>&lt;/a> entitled &lt;a href="http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1111/ecog.01714/abstract">&amp;lsquo;On the integration of biotic interaction and environmental constraints at the biogeographical scale&amp;rsquo;&lt;/a> where we develop some ideas about how ecological interactions and abiotic factors must be taken together into account to better predict species&amp;rsquo; distribution. As suggested during the editing process, we wrote a &lt;a href="http://www.ecography.org/blog/towards-integrated-theory-biogeography">blog post for &lt;em>Ecography&lt;/em>&lt;/a> that summarizes our paper. I think blog posts are an useful way to promote one&amp;rsquo;s work and also a good compromise between reading the abstract and reading the entire paper. We may also get more by reading the blog post than glancing over the paper.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>