<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>&lt;i class='fab fa-canadian-maple-leaf'>&lt;/i> EcoNotes on KevCaz's Website</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/econotes/</link><description>Recent content in &lt;i class='fab fa-canadian-maple-leaf'>&lt;/i> EcoNotes on KevCaz's Website</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Content under CC0 1.0 Universal unless otherwise specified.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 13 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://kevcaz.github.io/econotes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Releasing the research compendium for our Labmnivory paper</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/econotes/2021/publish_compendium/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/econotes/2021/publish_compendium/</guid><description>&amp;#x1f4e3; This post was first published on mccannlab.ca. Good news everyone! This week, our &amp;ldquo;Labmnivory&amp;rdquo; paper led by Marie Gutgesell has been accepted in Bioscience. Therefore, the time has come to release the code we promised explicitly in the manuscript.
Code for theoretical investigations will be made available on GitHub and archive on Zenodo upon manuscript acceptance.
For reproducibility&amp;rsquo;s sake, we&amp;rsquo;ve structured our Julia scripts as a research compendium which so far has been hosted on GitHub, in a private repository.</description></item><item><title>On the sensitivity of food webs to multiple stressors</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/econotes/2021/mulistressors/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/econotes/2021/mulistressors/</guid><description>Our latest work1 led by David Beauchesne is out since yesterday in Ecology Letters &amp;#x1f973;! This paper introduces a framework that allows the exploration of the impact of multiple stressors on food webs.
In the Anthropocene, human activities impact species is various ways. Multiple stressors frameworks attempt to account for their diversity and their joint effects (stressors may have antagonistic or synergistic effects). Most of such frameworks (if not all) are species-based, meaning that they account for the sensitivity of species to the stressors and the intensity of the stressor (e.</description></item><item><title>Corals, Algae, Fish and Humans</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/econotes/2021/corals/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/econotes/2021/corals/</guid><description>As I am jumping into a new project on coral reefs in the Carribeans, I thought it would make great sense for me to spend some time to get some basic ideas about corals, what&amp;rsquo;s currently threatening them and what are the consequences of the worldwide decline of coral cover.
Some basic knowledge about corals Corals are cnidarians, Cnidaria is a phylum that includes hydrae (Hydrozoa), jellyfish (Medusozoa), among others. Corals form colonies made of clones called polyps that are linked by a tissue called coenenchyme1.</description></item><item><title>Co-occurrence, not interaction!</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/econotes/2020/coocnotinter/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/econotes/2020/coocnotinter/</guid><description>This note is a short comment on the paper Guillaume Blanchet, Dominique Gravel and I recently published in Ecology Letters.
What information is contained in co-occurrence data? I don&amp;#39;t have a definitive answer to this question but assuming co-occurrence data are proxies for ecological interactions could lead to erroneous conclusions, we explain why in this new piece https://t.co/Ze9o7pfZNF
&amp;mdash; Kevin Cazelles (@KCazelles) May 20, 2020 What did we do? We basically went over 7 arguments to explain why the information in co-occurrence cannot be taken as a proxy for ecological interactions.</description></item><item><title>Never too late to publish your code!</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/econotes/2020/biogeonet/</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/econotes/2020/biogeonet/</guid><description>Since 2017, for every article I work on, I now do my best to release the code I used to obtain the results presented therein (see my research compendia in the software section). In my humble opinion, this is the least I can do cause the numerical part of a study (often a large part of my work) is relatively easy to reproduce, though it requires some time to master the tools to do so.</description></item><item><title>Homogenization of freshwater lakes</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/econotes/2019/homogenontario/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/econotes/2019/homogenontario/</guid><description>This was originally posted on https://mccannlab.ca/post/2019/09/20/homogenization-of-freshwater-lakes/
English version &amp;#x1f1ec;&amp;#x1f1e7; What happened to fish communities in Ontario lakes over the last few decades? We have been relentlessly looking for answers to this question! Indeed, we did our best to determine whether global change has affected those communities over the last 40 years. It turns out that fish communities in Ontario lakes are pretty different from what they were, but climate change does not explain those changes &amp;#x1f4a5;!</description></item><item><title>Towards an integrated theory of biogeography</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/econotes/2016/towards-an-integrated-theory-of-biogeography/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/econotes/2016/towards-an-integrated-theory-of-biogeography/</guid><description>Dominique Gravel, Nicolas Mouquet, David Mouillot and I have recently published a paper in Ecography entitled &amp;lsquo;On the integration of biotic interaction and environmental constraints at the biogeographical scale&amp;rsquo; where we develop some ideas about how ecological interactions and abiotic factors must be taken together into account to better predict species&amp;rsquo; distribution. As suggested during the editing process, we wrote a blog post for Ecography that summarizes our paper. I think blog posts are an useful way to promote one&amp;rsquo;s work and also a good compromise between reading the abstract and reading the entire paper.</description></item></channel></rss>