<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Biogeography on KevCaz's Website</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/tags/biogeography/</link><description>Recent content in Biogeography on KevCaz's Website</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Content under CC0 1.0 Universal unless otherwise specified.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 17 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://kevcaz.github.io/tags/biogeography/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Never too late to publish your code!</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/econotes/2020/biogeonet/</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/econotes/2020/biogeonet/</guid><description>&lt;p>Since 2017, for every article I work on, I now do my best to release the code I
used to obtain the results presented therein (see my research compendia in the
&lt;a href="../../software/">software section&lt;/a>). In my humble opinion, this is the least I can
do cause the numerical part of a study (often a large part of my work) is
relatively easy to reproduce, though it requires some time to master the tools
to do so. As I now perceived reproducibility of my work as a duty, I felt guilty regarding a paper I published back in 2015.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Towards an integrated theory of biogeography</title><link>https://kevcaz.github.io/econotes/2016/towards-an-integrated-theory-of-biogeography/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevcaz.github.io/econotes/2016/towards-an-integrated-theory-of-biogeography/</guid><description>&lt;p>Dominique Gravel, Nicolas Mouquet, David Mouillot and I have recently published a paper in &lt;a href="http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/10.1111/(ISSN)1600-0587">&lt;em>Ecography&lt;/em>&lt;/a> entitled &lt;a href="http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1111/ecog.01714/abstract">&amp;lsquo;On the integration of biotic interaction and environmental constraints at the biogeographical scale&amp;rsquo;&lt;/a> where we develop some ideas about how ecological interactions and abiotic factors must be taken together into account to better predict species&amp;rsquo; distribution. As suggested during the editing process, we wrote a &lt;a href="http://www.ecography.org/blog/towards-integrated-theory-biogeography">blog post for &lt;em>Ecography&lt;/em>&lt;/a> that summarizes our paper. I think blog posts are an useful way to promote one&amp;rsquo;s work and also a good compromise between reading the abstract and reading the entire paper. We may also get more by reading the blog post than glancing over the paper.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>